[{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Both the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual contain many aspects of a corporate security policy  - Acceptable Use of Internet/eMail/Phone and Consent to monitoring, for example.  Other aspects are missing such as defined security roles & responsibilities.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Has an information security policy document been approved by management, and published and communicated to all employees and relevant external parties?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual contain some aspects of a corporate security policy, but neither document has this verbiage within.","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","question":"Does the information security policy document state management's commitment and set out the organization's approach to managing information security?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual contain some aspects of a corporate security policy, but neither document has this verbiage within.","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","question":"Does the information security policy document contain a  statement concerning a definition of information security, its overall objectives and scope and the importance of security as an enabling mechanism for information sharing?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual contain some aspects of a corporate security policy, but neither document has this verbiage within.","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","question":"Does the information security policy document contain a  statement concerning a statement of management intent, supporting the goals and principles of information security in line with the business strategy and objectives?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual contain some aspects of a corporate security policy, but neither document has this verbiage within.","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","question":"Does the information security policy document contain a  statement concerning a framework for setting control objectives and controls, including the structure of risk assessment and risk management?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual contain some aspects of a corporate security policy, but neither document has this verbiage within.","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","question":"Does the information security policy document contain a  statement concerning a brief explanation of the security policies, principles, standards, and compliance requirements of particular importance to the organization, including:  (1) compliance with legislative, regulatory, and contractual requirements; (2) security education, training, and awareness requirements; (3) business continuity management; (4) consequences of information security policy violations?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Section 403 of the IT Procedure Manual covers this topic regarding virus reporting, but not other types of security incidents.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the information security policy document contain a  statement concerning a definition of general and specific responsibilities for information security management, including reporting information security incidents?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Information security policy document","question":"Does the information security policy document contain a  statement concerning references to documentation which may support the policy, e.g. more detailed security policies and procedures for specific information systems or security rules users should comply with?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual are located on the corporate intranet.   I'm not sure as to the frequency of communication that the documents exist there.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Review of Informational Security Policy","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Has this information security policy been communicated throughout the organization to users in a form that is relevant, accessible and understandable to the intended reader?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual don't seem to contain sensitive information.   I don't believe either document is communicated outside of the organization.","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Review of Informational Security Policy","question":"If the information security policy is distributed outside the organization, has care been taken not to disclose sensitive information?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Cam - No","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Review of Informational Security Policy","question":"Has the information security policy been reviewed at planned intervals or if significant changes occur to ensure its continuing suitability, adequacy, and effectiveness?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"customer_response":"Cam - No","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Review of Informational Security Policy","question":"Does the information security policy have an owner who has approved management responsibility for the development, review, and evaluation of the security policy?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"customer_response":"Cam - No","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Review of Informational Security Policy","question":"Are there defined management review procedures, including a schedule or period of the review?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"N/R due to prior No response(s) on this topic.","domain":"Security Policy","objective":"Review of Informational Security Policy","question":"Is management approval for the revised policy obtained?","reason":"Management should set a clear policy direction in line with business objectives and demonstrate support for, and commitment to, information security through the issue and maintenance of an information security policy across the organization.","section":"Information Security Policy","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Clear direction - Yes due to Employee Handbook and IT Procedure Manual.\r\nDemonstrated Commitment / Acknowledgement - No due to lack of information security awareness training or refresher training\r\nExplicit assignment - Partial.  A CIO is designated in a acting capacity.  There is no security manager or security engineer though.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Does management actively support security within the organization through clear direction, demonstrated commitment, explicit assignment, and acknowledgment of information security responsibilities?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Not stated in any documentation provided during the audit.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","question":"Does management ensure that information security goals are identified, meet the organizational requirements, and are integrated in relevant processes?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Both the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual contain many aspects of a corporate security policy.  They are reviewed/approved by Management","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does management formulate, review, and approve information security policy?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Both the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual contain many aspects of a corporate security policy.  Both documents are dated from early 2015.  During the audit it was stated by the CIO that the documents were currently being updated.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does management review the effectiveness of the implementation of the information security policy?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":62.5},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"It was stated by several people that I interviewed that Information Security Awareness isn't part of the refresher or monthly training programs.  For the most part, Information Security training seems to be covered during the onboarding process and post security incident.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","question":"Does management provide clear direction and visible management support for security initiatives?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Technical resources - Staff / Software Tools - No","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","question":"Does management provide the resources needed for information security?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No documented in the Employee Handbook or IT Procedure Manual.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","question":"Does management approve assignment of specific roles and responsibilities for information security across the organization?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"It was stated by several people that I interviewed that Information Security Awareness isn't part of the refresher or monthly training programs.  For the most part, Information Security training seems to be covered during the onboarding process and post security incident.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","question":"Does management initiate plans and programs to maintain information security awareness?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"None of the IT systems we audited had adequate security controls implemented.  All had failing scores.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","question":"Does management ensure that the implementation of information security controls is coordinated across the organization?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Movement Mortgage does consult with external specialists to review and coordinate information security services.  Some of the findings from the 2014 Security Audit are being addressed.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Management Commitment to Information Security","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Does management identify the needs for internal or external specialist information security advice, and review and coordinate results of the advice throughout the organization?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Are information security activities coordinated by representatives from different parts of the organization with relevant roles and job functions?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does information security coordination involve the co-operation and collaboration of managers, users, administrators, application designers, auditors and security personnel, and specialist skills in areas such as insurance, legal issues, human resources, IT or risk management?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does the information security coordination activity ensure that security activities are executed in compliance with the information security policy?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does the information security coordination activity identify how to handle non-compliances?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does the information security coordination activity approve methodologies and processes for information security, (e.g. risk assessment and information classification)?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does the information security coordination activity identify significant threat changes and exposure of information and information processing facilities to threats?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does the information security coordination activity assess the adequacy and co-ordinate the implementation of information security controls?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"It was stated by several people that I interviewed that Information Security Awareness isn't part of the refresher or monthly training programs.  For the most part, Information Security training seems to be covered during the onboarding process and post security incident.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does the information security coordination activity effectively promote information security education, training and awareness throughout the organization?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Cam - No.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"Does the information security coordination activity evaluate information received from the monitoring and reviewing of information security incidents, and recommend appropriate actions in response to identified information security incidents?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't dive deep enough into this area during the audit. Perhaps in the future.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Information Security coordination","question":"If the organization does not use a separate cross-functional group, (e.g. because such a group is not appropriate for the organization‟s size), are the actions described above undertaken by another suitable management body or individual manager?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"The employee handbook and IT Procedure manual contain some aspects of a corporate security policy, but neither document has this verbiage within.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Are all information security responsibilities clearly defined?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"N/R Based on prior No response(s) related to this question.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Is allocation of information security responsibilities done in accordance with the information security policy?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Both the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are responsibilities for the protection of individual assets and for carrying out specific security processes clearly identified?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"auditor_notes":"Not Applicable.  Policies are for the Corporate Site only.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Is this responsibility supplemented, where necessary, with more detailed guidance for specific sites and information processing facilities?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Are local responsibilities for the protection of assets and for carrying out specific security processes, such as business continuity planning, clearly defined?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Do individuals with allocated security responsibilities who delegate security tasks to others; determine that any delegated tasks have been correctly performed?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Both the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are areas for which individuals are responsible clearly stated?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Are the assets and security processes associated with each particular system identified and clearly defined?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"N/R Based on prior No response(s) related to this question.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Is the entity responsible for each asset or security process assigned and the details of this responsibility documented?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Allocation of Information Security responsibilities","question":"Are authorization levels clearly defined and documented?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Authorization process for Information processing facilities","question":"Has a management authorization process for new information processing facilities been defined and implemented?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Authorization process for Information processing facilities","question":"Has the authorization process considered whether new facilities should have appropriate user management authorization, authorizing their purpose and use?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Authorization process for Information processing facilities","question":"Has the authorization process considered whether authorization should also be obtained from the manager responsible for maintaining the local information system security environment to ensure that all relevant security policies and requirements are met?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Authorization process for Information processing facilities","question":"Has the authorization process considered whether where necessary, hardware and software should be checked to ensure that they are compatible with other system components?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Authorization process for Information processing facilities","question":"Has the authorization process considered whether the use of personal or privately owned information processing facilities, (e.g. laptops, home-computers or hand-held devices, for processing business information), may introduce new vulnerabilities and necessary controls should be identified and implemented?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Confidentiality Agreements","question":"Are requirements for confidentiality or non-disclosure agreements reflecting the organization‟s needs for the protection of information identified and regularly reviewed?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Verified by reveiwing the NDA I signed.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Confidentiality Agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Do confidentiality or non-disclosure agreements address the requirement to protect confidential information using legally enforceable terms?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"The NDA seemed to cover many of the topics.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Confidentiality Agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are the following elements considered when identifying requirements for confidentiality or nondisclosure agreements:&#10;a) a definition of the information to be protected (e.g. confidential information);&#10;b) expected duration of an agreement, including cases where confidentiality might need to be maintained indefinitely;&#10;c) required actions when an agreement is terminated;&#10;d) responsibilities and actions of signatories to avoid unauthorized information disclosure (such as „need to know‟);&#10;e) ownership of information, trade secrets and intellectual property, and how this relates to the protection of confidential information;&#10;f) the permitted use of confidential information, and rights of the signatory to use information;&#10;g) the right to audit and monitor activities that involve confidential information;&#10;h) process for notification and reporting of unauthorized disclosure or confidential information breaches;&#10;i) terms for information to be returned or destroyed at agreement cessation; and&#10;j) expected actions to be taken in case of a breach of this agreement?Are the following elements considered when identifying requirements for confidentiality or nondisclosure agreements:&#10;a) a definition of the information to be protected (e.g. confidential information);&#10;b) expected duration of an agreement, including cases where confidentiality might need to be maintained indefinitely;&#10;c) required actions when an agreement is terminated;&#10;d) responsibilities and actions of signatories to avoid unauthorized information disclosure (such as „need to know‟);&#10;e) ownership of information, trade secrets and intellectual property, and how this relates to the protection of confidential information;&#10;f) the permitted use of confidential information, and rights of the signatory to use information;&#10;g) the right to audit and monitor activities that involve confidential information;&#10;h) process for notification and reporting of unauthorized disclosure or confidential information breaches;&#10;i) terms for information to be returned or destroyed at agreement cessation; and&#10;j) expected actions to be taken in case of a breach of this agreement?Are the following elements considered when identifying requirements for confidentiality or nondisclosure agreements:&#10;a) a definition of the information to be protected (e.g. confidential information);&#10;b) expected duration of an agreement, including cases where confidentiality might need to be maintained indefinitely;&#10;c) required actions when an agreement is terminated;&#10;d) responsibilities and actions of signatories to avoid unauthorized information disclosure (such as „need to know‟);&#10;e) ownership of information, trade secrets and intellectual property, and how this relates to the protection of confidential information;&#10;f) the permitted use of confidential information, and rights of the signatory to use information;&#10;g) the right to audit and monitor activities that involve confidential information;&#10;h) process for notification and reporting of unauthorized disclosure or confidential information breaches;&#10;i) terms for information to be returned or destroyed at agreement cessation; and&#10;j) expected actions to be taken in case of a breach of this agreement?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Confidentiality Agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Do confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements comply with all applicable laws and regulations for the jurisdiction to which it applies?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Confidentiality Agreements","question":"Are requirements for confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements reviewed periodically and when changes occur that influence these requirements?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Contact with Authorities","question":"Are appropriate contacts with relevant authorities maintained?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Contact with Authorities","question":"Does the organization have procedures in place that specify when and by whom authorities (e.g. law enforcement, fire department, and supervisory authorities) should be contacted?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Neither the employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual address this topic.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Contact with Authorities","question":"Has the organization identified how information security incidents should be reported in a timely manner if it is suspected that laws may have been broken?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Contact with special interest groups","question":"Are appropriate contacts with special interest groups or other specialist security forums and professional associations maintained?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Contact with special interest groups","question":"Is membership in special interest groups or forums considered as a means to:&#10;a) improve knowledge about best practices and staying up to date with relevant security information;&#10;b) ensure the understanding of the information security environment is current and complete;&#10;c) receive early warnings of alerts, advisories, and patches pertaining to attacks and vulnerabilities;&#10;d) gain access to specialist information security advice;&#10;e) share and exchange information about new technologies, products, threats, or vulnerabilities;&#10;f) provide suitable liaison points when dealing with information security incidents?Is membership in special interest groups or forums considered as a means to:&#10;a) improve knowledge about best practices and staying up to date with relevant security information;&#10;b) ensure the understanding of the information security environment is current and complete;&#10;c) receive early warnings of alerts, advisories, and patches pertaining to attacks and vulnerabilities;&#10;d) gain access to specialist information security advice;&#10;e) share and exchange information about new technologies, products, threats, or vulnerabilities;&#10;f) provide suitable liaison points when dealing with information security incidents?Is membership in special interest groups or forums considered as a means to:&#10;a) improve knowledge about best practices and staying up to date with relevant security information;&#10;b) ensure the understanding of the information security environment is current and complete;&#10;c) receive early warnings of alerts, advisories, and patches pertaining to attacks and vulnerabilities;&#10;d) gain access to specialist information security advice;&#10;e) share and exchange information about new technologies, products, threats, or vulnerabilities;&#10;f) provide suitable liaison points when dealing with information security incidents?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Reviewed several external party agreements.  Verbiage regarding protection of NPI was covered in one of the provided agreements.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Contact with special interest groups","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"If information sharing agreements are established to improve cooperation and coordination of security issues, do those agreements identify requirements for the protection of sensitive information?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Movement Mortgage has comissioned 2 Independent IT Security Audits since 2014.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Independent review of Information Security","question":"Is the organization's approach to managing information security and its implementation (i.e. control objectives, controls, policies, processes, and procedures for information security) reviewed independently at planned intervals, or when significant changes to the security implementation occur?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Independent review of Information Security","question":"Is the independent review initiated by management?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Independent review of Information Security","question":"Does the review include assessing opportunities for improvement and the need for changes to the approach to security, including the policy and control objectives?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Independent review of Information Security","question":"Is the review carried out by individuals independent of the area under review, (e.g. the internal audit function, an independent manager or a third party organization specializing in such reviews)?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Independent review of Information Security","question":"Do the individuals carrying out these reviews have the appropriate skills and experience?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Independent review of Information Security","question":"Are the results of the independent review recorded and reported to the management who initiated the review?  Are these records maintained?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Independent review of Information Security","question":"Does management consider corrective actions if the independent review identifies that the organization‟s approach and implementation to managing information security is inadequate or not compliant with the direction for information security stated in the information security policy document?","reason":"A management framework should be established to initiate and control the implementation of information security within the organization.&#10;Management should approve the information security policy, assign security roles and co-ordinate and review the implementation of security across the organization.&#10;&#10;If necessary, a source of specialist information security advice should be established and made available within the organization. Contacts with external security specialists or groups, including relevant authorities, should be developed to keep up with industrial trends, monitor standards and assessment methods and provide suitable liaison points when handling information security incidents.&#10;&#10;A multi-disciplinary approach to information security should be encouraged.","section":"Internal organization","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":2,"text":"Reported on Some Systems","value":0.5},"customer_response":"Processes are implemented on about 1/3 of org's external party agreements. - Richard Jenkins","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Identification of risks related to external parties","policy_defined":{"id":3,"text":"Written Policy","value":0.75},"question":"Are the risks to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities from business processes involving external parties identified and appropriate controls implemented before granting access?","reason":"The security of the organization‟s information and information processing facilities should not be reduced by the introduction of external party products or services. Any access to the organization‟s information processing facilities and processing and communication of information by external parties should be controlled. Where there is a business need for working with external parties that may require access to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities, or in obtaining or providing a product and service from or to an external party, a risk assessment should be carried out to determine security implications and control requirements. Controls should be agreed and defined in an agreement with the external party.","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":58.333333333333336},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Processes are implemented on about 1/3 of org's external party agreements. - Richard Jenkins\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers - An annual certification is performed for Tier 1, 2 and 3 external parties.  Tier 1, 2, and 3 external parties have access to NPI.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Identification of risks related to external parties","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Where there is a need to allow an external party access to the information processing facilities or information of an organization, is a risk assessment carried out to identify any requirements for specific controls?","reason":"The security of the organization‟s information and information processing facilities should not be reduced by the introduction of external party products or services. Any access to the organization‟s information processing facilities and processing and communication of information by external parties should be controlled. Where there is a business need for working with external parties that may require access to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities, or in obtaining or providing a product and service from or to an external party, a risk assessment should be carried out to determine security implications and control requirements. Controls should be agreed and defined in an agreement with the external party.","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Identification of risks related to external parties","question":"Do the identification of risks related to external party access take into account the following issues:&#10;a) the information processing facilities an external party is required to access;&#10;b) the type of access the external party will have to the information and information processing facilities, e.g.:&#10;     1) physical access, e.g. to offices, computer rooms,   filing cabinets;&#10;     2) logical access, e.g. to an organization‟s databases, information systems;&#10;     3) network connectivity between the organization‟s and the external party‟s network(s), e.g. permanent connection, remote access;&#10;     4) whether the access is taking place on-site or off-site;&#10;c) the value and sensitivity of the information involved, and its criticality for business operations;&#10;d) the controls necessary to protect information that is not intended to be accessible by external parties;&#10;e) the external party personnel involved in handling the organization‟s information;&#10;f) how the organization or personnel authorized to have access can be identified, the authorization verified, and how often this needs to be reconfirmed;&#10;g) the different means and controls employed by the external party when storing, processing, communicating, sharing and exchanging information;&#10;h) the impact of access not being available to the external party when required, and the external party entering or receiving inaccurate or misleading information;&#10;i) practices and procedures to deal with information security incidents and potential damages, and the terms and conditions for the continuation of external party access in the case of an information security incident;&#10;j) legal and regulatory requirements and other contractual obligations relevant to the external party that should be taken into account;&#10;k) how the interests of any other stakeholders may be affected by the arrangements?Do the identification of risks related to external party access take into account the following issues:&#10;a) the information processing facilities an external party is required to access;&#10;b) the type of access the external party will have to the information and information processing facilities, e.g.:&#10;     1) physical access, e.g. to offices, computer rooms,   filing cabinets;&#10;     2) logical access, e.g. to an organization‟s databases, information systems;&#10;     3) network connectivity between the organization‟s and the external party‟s network(s), e.g. permanent connection, remote access;&#10;     4) whether the access is taking place on-site or off-site;&#10;c) the value and sensitivity of the information involved, and its criticality for business operations;&#10;d) the controls necessary to protect information that is not intended to be accessible by external parties;&#10;e) the external party personnel involved in handling the organization‟s information;&#10;f) how the organization or personnel authorized to have access can be identified, the authorization verified, and how often this needs to be reconfirmed;&#10;g) the different means and controls employed by the external party when storing, processing, communicating, sharing and exchanging information;&#10;h) the impact of access not being available to the external party when required, and the external party entering or receiving inaccurate or misleading information;&#10;i) practices and procedures to deal with information security incidents and potential damages, and the terms and conditions for the continuation of external party access in the case of an information security incident;&#10;j) legal and regulatory requirements and other contractual obligations relevant to the external party that should be taken into account;&#10;k) how the interests of any other stakeholders may be affected by the arrangements?","reason":"The security of the organization‟s information and information processing facilities should not be reduced by the introduction of external party products or services. Any access to the organization‟s information processing facilities and processing and communication of information by external parties should be controlled. Where there is a business need for working with external parties that may require access to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities, or in obtaining or providing a product and service from or to an external party, a risk assessment should be carried out to determine security implications and control requirements. Controls should be agreed and defined in an agreement with the external party.","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Verified during interview with CIO as well.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Richard Jenkins stated that this control is implemented.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Identification of risks related to external parties","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Is access by external parties to the organization’s information withheld until the appropriate controls have been implemented and, where feasible, a contract has been signed defining the terms and conditions for the connection or access and the working arrangement?","reason":"The security of the organization‟s information and information processing facilities should not be reduced by the introduction of external party products or services. Any access to the organization‟s information processing facilities and processing and communication of information by external parties should be controlled. Where there is a business need for working with external parties that may require access to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities, or in obtaining or providing a product and service from or to an external party, a risk assessment should be carried out to determine security implications and control requirements. Controls should be agreed and defined in an agreement with the external party.","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Implemented on agreements that he has reviewed.  Cannot confirm for all agreements.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Identification of risks related to external parties","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are all security requirements resulting from work with external parties or internal controls reflected by the agreement with the external party?","reason":"The security of the organization‟s information and information processing facilities should not be reduced by the introduction of external party products or services. Any access to the organization‟s information processing facilities and processing and communication of information by external parties should be controlled. Where there is a business need for working with external parties that may require access to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities, or in obtaining or providing a product and service from or to an external party, a risk assessment should be carried out to determine security implications and control requirements. Controls should be agreed and defined in an agreement with the external party.","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Implemented on agreements that he has reviewed.  Cannot confirm for all agreements.\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers -  Haven't reviewed all contracts, but they are for most critical (tier 1 and 2).","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Identification of risks related to external parties","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization ensure that the external party is aware of their obligations, and accepts the responsibilities and liabilities involved in accessing, processing, communicating, or managing the organization‟s information and information processing facilities?","reason":"The security of the organization‟s information and information processing facilities should not be reduced by the introduction of external party products or services. Any access to the organization‟s information processing facilities and processing and communication of information by external parties should be controlled. Where there is a business need for working with external parties that may require access to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities, or in obtaining or providing a product and service from or to an external party, a risk assessment should be carried out to determine security implications and control requirements. Controls should be agreed and defined in an agreement with the external party.","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Richard Jenkins - Implemented on agreements that he has reviewed.  Cannot confirm for all agreements.\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers -","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Identification of risks related to external parties","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are controls identified and applied to administer external party access to information processing facilities, where information might be put at risk by external parties with inadequate security management?","reason":"The security of the organization‟s information and information processing facilities should not be reduced by the introduction of external party products or services. Any access to the organization‟s information processing facilities and processing and communication of information by external parties should be controlled. Where there is a business need for working with external parties that may require access to the organization‟s information and information processing facilities, or in obtaining or providing a product and service from or to an external party, a risk assessment should be carried out to determine security implications and control requirements. Controls should be agreed and defined in an agreement with the external party.","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"auditor_notes":"Customers do not access information or assets belonging to Movement Mortgage.  Only external parties that have signed exchange agreements may do this.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security while dealing with customers","question":"Are all identified security requirements addressed before giving customers access to the organization’s information or assets?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"auditor_notes":"N/A Based on prior N/A response(s) related to this question.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security while dealing with customers","question":"Are the following terms considered to address security prior to giving customers access to any of the organization‟s assets (depending on the type and extent of access given, not all of them might apply):&#10;a) asset protection, including:&#10;1) procedures to protect the organization‟s assets, including information and software, and management of known vulnerabilities;&#10;2) procedures to determine whether any compromise of the assets, e.g. loss or modification of data, has occurred;&#10;3) integrity;&#10;4) restrictions on copying and disclosing information;&#10;b) description of the product or service to be provided;&#10;c) the different reasons, requirements, and benefits for customer access;&#10;d) access control policy, covering:&#10;1) permitted access methods, and the control and use of unique identifiers such as user IDs and passwords;&#10;2) an authorization process for user access and privileges;&#10;3) a statement that all access that is not explicitly authorized is forbidden;&#10;4) a process for revoking access rights or interrupting the connection between systems;&#10;e) arrangements for reporting, notification, and investigation of information inaccuracies (e.g. of personal details), information security incidents and security breaches;&#10;f) a description of each service to be made available;&#10;g) the target level of service and unacceptable levels of service;&#10;h) the right to monitor, and revoke, any activity related to the organization‟s assets;&#10;i) the respective liabilities of the organization and the customer;&#10;j) responsibilities with respect to legal matters and how it is ensured that the legal requirements are met, e.g. data protection legislation, especially taking into account different national legal systems if the agreement involves co-operation with customers in other countries;&#10;k) intellectual property rights (IPRs) and copyright assignment and protection of any collaborative work?Are the following terms considered to address security prior to giving customers access to any of the organization‟s assets (depending on the type and extent of access given, not all of them might apply):&#10;a) asset protection, including:&#10;1) procedures to protect the organization‟s assets, including information and software, and management of known vulnerabilities;&#10;2) procedures to determine whether any compromise of the assets, e.g. loss or modification of data, has occurred;&#10;3) integrity;&#10;4) restrictions on copying and disclosing information;&#10;b) description of the product or service to be provided;&#10;c) the different reasons, requirements, and benefits for customer access;&#10;d) access control policy, covering:&#10;1) permitted access methods, and the control and use of unique identifiers such as user IDs and passwords;&#10;2) an authorization process for user access and privileges;&#10;3) a statement that all access that is not explicitly authorized is forbidden;&#10;4) a process for revoking access rights or interrupting the connection between systems;&#10;e) arrangements for reporting, notification, and investigation of information inaccuracies (e.g. of personal details), information security incidents and security breaches;&#10;f) a description of each service to be made available;&#10;g) the target level of service and unacceptable levels of service;&#10;h) the right to monitor, and revoke, any activity related to the organization‟s assets;&#10;i) the respective liabilities of the organization and the customer;&#10;j) responsibilities with respect to legal matters and how it is ensured that the legal requirements are met, e.g. data protection legislation, especially taking into account different national legal systems if the agreement involves co-operation with customers in other countries;&#10;k) intellectual property rights (IPRs) and copyright assignment and protection of any collaborative work?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Justin noted that references to subcontractors were mentioned in the Process Unity Onboarding.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Richard Jenkins - doesn't believe this is included in the cuurent agreement policy.\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers -","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security while dealing with customers","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Do agreements granting external party access include allowance for designation of other eligible parties and conditions for their access and involvement?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":37.5},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers -","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security in third party agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Do agreements with third parties involving accessing, processing, communicating or managing the organization’s information or information processing facilities, or adding products or services to information processing facilities cover all relevant security requirements?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Language in these agreements are clear based on review of sample provided.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Richard Jenkins - Yes or the agreement would be redone.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security in third party agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the agreement ensure that there is no misunderstanding between the organization and the third party?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Richard Jenkins - Yes, this is always reviewed by our in-house counsel.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security in third party agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization satisfy themselves as to the indemnity of the third party?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Richard Jenkins - Yes.  Legal reviews all agreements for this topic.\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers - Due care isn't happening because we aren't auditing the 3rd parties directly.","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security in third party agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Since agreements can vary considerably for different organizations and among the different types of third parties - is due care taken to include all identified risks and security requirements in the agreements?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"information security management is in-house","domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security in third party agreements","question":"If information security management is outsourced, do the agreements address how the third party will guarantee that adequate security, as defined by the risk assessment, will be maintained, and how security will be adapted to identify and deal with changes to risks?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Noted that this wasn't the case on all external party agreements.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security in third party agreements","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Do agreements granting third party access include allowance for designation of other eligible parties and conditions for their access and involvement?","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Organization of Information Security","objective":"Addressing security in third party agreements","question":"Are the following items considered for inclusion in the agreement in order to satisfy the identified security requirements:&#10;a) the information security policy;&#10;b) controls to ensure asset protection&#10;c) user and administrator training in methods, procedures, and security;&#10;d) ensuring user awareness for information security responsibilities and issues;&#10;e) provision for the transfer of personnel, where appropriate;&#10;f) responsibilities regarding hardware and software installation and maintenance;&#10;g) a clear reporting structure and agreed reporting formats;&#10;h) a clear and specified process of change management;&#10;i) access control policy&#10;j) arrangements for reporting, notification, and investigation of information security incidents and security breaches, as well as violations of the requirements stated in the agreement;&#10;k) a description of the product or service to be provided, and a description of the information to be made available along with its security classification;&#10;l) the target level of service and unacceptable levels of service;&#10;m) the definition of verifiable performance criteria, their monitoring and reporting;&#10;n) the right to monitor, and revoke, any activity related to the organization‟s assets;&#10;o) the right to audit responsibilities defined in the agreement, to have those audits carried out by a third party&#10;p) the establishment of an escalation process for problem resolution;&#10;q) service continuity requirements, including measures for availability and reliability, in accordance with an organization‟s business priorities;&#10;r) the respective liabilities of the parties to the agreement;&#10;s) responsibilities with respect to legal matters and how it is ensured that the legal requirements are met, e.g. data protection legislation, especially taking into account different national legal systems if the agreement involves co-operation with organizations in other countries;&#10;t) intellectual property rights (IPRs) and copyright assignment and protection of any collaborative work;&#10;u) involvement of the third party with subcontractors, and the security controls these subcontractors need to implement;&#10;v) conditions for renegotiation/termination of agreements","section":"External parties","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":3,"text":"Automated on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":3,"text":"Reported on Most Systems","value":0.75},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Inventory of Assets","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Are all assets clearly identified and an inventory of all primary and secondary assets drawn up and maintained?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":56.25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"The organization has identified most computing assets using automated tools.    The importance of the assets has not been documented as part of a risk assessment or Continuity of Operations Plan.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":3,"text":"Automated on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":3,"text":"Reported on Most Systems","value":0.75},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Inventory of Assets","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Has the organization identified all assets and documented the importance of these assets?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":3,"text":"Automated on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":3,"text":"Reported on Most Systems","value":0.75},"customer_response":"KACE can capture most of the information.  Business value not captured.","domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Inventory of Assets","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Does the asset inventory include all information necessary in order to recover from a disaster, including type of asset, format, location, backup information, license information, and a business value?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":56.25},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Inventory of Assets","question":"Does the inventory ensure that the content is aligned with the business function?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - Managed in spreadsheet.    Will be managed in KACE.","domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Inventory of Assets","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Is ownership and information classification agreed and documented for each of the assets?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Inventory of Assets","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Based on the importance of the asset, its business value and its security classification, are levels of protection commensurate with the importance of the assets identified?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - from an accounting perspective, they are owned by the departments.  From a management perspective, IT is responsibile for issuing/reclaimation.","domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Ownership of Assets","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Are all information and assets associated with information processing facilities owned by a designated part of the organization?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Ownership of Assets","question":"Is the asset owner responsible for:<br>;a) ensuring that information and assets associated with information processing facilities are appropriately classified<br> b) defining and periodically reviewing access restrictions and classifications, taking into account applicable access control policies?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Acceptible use is part of the employee handbook.  Section 800/801.","domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Acceptable use of assets","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are rules for the acceptable use of information and assets associated with information processing facilities identified, documented, and implemented?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Not for 3rd parties.","domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Acceptable use of assets","question":"Are all employees, contractors and third party users required to follow rules for the acceptable use of information and assets associated with information processing facilities, including:&#10;a) rules for electronic mail and internet usages;&#10;b) guidelines for the use of mobile devices, especially for the use outside the premises of the organization?Are all employees, contractors and third party users required to follow rules for the acceptable use of information and assets associated with information processing facilities, including:&#10;a) rules for electronic mail and internet usages;&#10;b) guidelines for the use of mobile devices, especially for the use outside the premises of the organization?","reason":"All assets should be accounted for and have a nominated owner. Owners should be identified for all assets and the responsibility for the maintenance of appropriate controls should be assigned. The implementation of specific controls may be delegated by the owner as appropriate but the owner remains responsible for the proper protection of the assets.","section":"Responsibility for assets","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Informal policy for retaining laptop hard drives in laptops and NAS.","domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Is information and assets classified in terms of its value, legal requirements, sensitivity, and criticality to the organization?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and critical. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","question":"Do classifications and associated protective controls for information take account of business needs for sharing or restricting information and the business impacts associated with such needs?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","question":"Do classification guidelines include conventions for initial classification and reclassification over time; in accordance with some predetermined access control policy?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","question":"Is it the responsibility of the asset owner to define the classification of an asset, periodically review it, and ensure it is kept up to date and at the appropriate level?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","question":"Does the classification take account of the aggregation effect mentioned in ISO/IEC 27002:2005 (E) §10.7.2?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","question":"Is consideration given to the number of classification categories and the benefits to be gained from their use?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","question":"Is care taken in interpreting classification labels on documents from other organizations, which may have different definitions for the same or similarly named labels?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Classification guidelines","question":"Information often ceases to be sensitive or critical after a certain period of time, for example, when the information has been made public. Are these aspects taken into account, as over-classification can lead to the implementation of unnecessary controls resulting in additional expense?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Information labeling and handling","question":"Has an appropriate set of procedures for information labeling and handling been developed and implemented in accordance with the classification scheme adopted by the organization?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Information labeling and handling","question":"Does output from systems containing information that is classified as being sensitive or critical carry an appropriate classification label (in the output)?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Information labeling and handling","question":"Does the labeling reflect the classification according to the rules established above? (Items for consideration include printed reports, screen displays, recorded media e.g. tapes, disks, CDs, electronic messages, and file transfers)?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Information labeling and handling","question":"For each classification level, are the handling procedures including the secure processing, storage, transmission, declassification, and destruction defined?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Information labeling and handling","question":"For each classification level, do the handling procedures include the procedures for chain of custody and logging of any security relevant event?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Asset Management","objective":"Information labeling and handling","question":"Do agreements with other organizations that include information sharing include procedures to identify the classification of that information and to interpret the classification labels from other organizations?","reason":"Information should be classified to indicate the need, priorities, and expected degree of protection when handling the information. Information has varying degrees of sensitivity and criticality. Some items may require an additional level of protection or special handling. An information classification scheme should be used to define an appropriate set of protection levels and communicate the need for special handling measures.","section":"Information classification","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Roles and responsibilities","question":"Are security roles and responsibilities of employees, contractors and third party users defined and documented in accordance with the organization‟s information security policy?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Roles and responsibilities","question":"Do security roles and responsibilities include the requirement to:&#10;a) implement and act in accordance with the organization‟s information security policies;&#10;b) protect assets from unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, destruction or interference;&#10;c) execute particular security processes or activities;&#10;d) ensure responsibility is assigned to the individual for actions taken;&#10;e) report security events or potential events or other security risks to the organization?Do security roles and responsibilities include the requirement to:&#10;a) implement and act in accordance with the organization‟s information security policies;&#10;b) protect assets from unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, destruction or interference;&#10;c) execute particular security processes or activities;&#10;d) ensure responsibility is assigned to the individual for actions taken;&#10;e) report security events or potential events or other security risks to the organization?Do security roles and responsibilities include the requirement to:&#10;a) implement and act in accordance with the organization‟s information security policies;&#10;b) protect assets from unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, destruction or interference;&#10;c) execute particular security processes or activities;&#10;d) ensure responsibility is assigned to the individual for actions taken;&#10;e) report security events or potential events or other security risks to the organization?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Roles and responsibilities","question":"Are security roles and responsibilities defined and clearly communicated to job candidates during the pre-employment process?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"customer_response":"3rd Party Vendor Management.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Roles and responsibilities","question":"Are security roles and responsibilities for individuals not engaged via the organization‟s employment process, (e.g. engaged via a third party organization), also clearly defined and communicated?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood -  Background Checks done through Universal Background Screening Application.\r\n\r\nAll employees undergo a background check.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","policy_defined":{"id":3,"text":"Written Policy","value":0.75},"question":"Are background verification checks on all candidates for employment, contractors, and third party users carried out in accordance with relevant laws, regulations and ethics, and proportional to the business requirements, the classification of the information to be accessed, and the perceived risks?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Handled by Talents and Recruiting Team.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","question":"Do verification checks take into account all relevant privacy, protection of personal data and/or employment based legislation, and where permitted, include the following:&#10;a) availability of satisfactory character references, e.g. one business and one personal;&#10;b) a check (for completeness and accuracy) of the applicant‟s curriculum vitae;&#10;c) confirmation of claimed academic and professional qualifications;&#10;d) independent identity check (passport or similar document);&#10;e) more detailed checks, such as credit checks or checks of criminal records?Do verification checks take into account all relevant privacy, protection of personal data and/or employment based legislation, and where permitted, include the following:&#10;a) availability of satisfactory character references, e.g. one business and one personal;&#10;b) a check (for completeness and accuracy) of the applicant‟s curriculum vitae;&#10;c) confirmation of claimed academic and professional qualifications;&#10;d) independent identity check (passport or similar document);&#10;e) more detailed checks, such as credit checks or checks of criminal records?Do verification checks take into account all relevant privacy, protection of personal data and/or employment based legislation, and where permitted, include the following:&#10;a) availability of satisfactory character references, e.g. one business and one personal;&#10;b) a check (for completeness and accuracy) of the applicant‟s curriculum vitae;&#10;c) confirmation of claimed academic and professional qualifications;&#10;d) independent identity check (passport or similar document);&#10;e) more detailed checks, such as credit checks or checks of criminal records?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Sean Wilkins.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","question":"Does the organization also consider further, more detailed checks, where a job, either on initial appointment or on promotion, involves the person having access to information processing facilities, and in particular if these are handling sensitive information, e.g. financial information or highly confidential information?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","question":"Does the organization‟s procedures define criteria and limitations for verification checks, e.g. who is eligible to screen people, and how, when and why verification checks are carried out?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Temps undergo this process.\r\n\r\nFor External - See Richard Jenkins.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","question":"Is a screening process also carried out for contractors, and third party users?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"customer_response":"For External - See Richard Jenkins.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","question":"Where contractors are provided through an agency does the contract with the agency clearly specify the agency‟s responsibilities for screening and the notification procedures they need to follow if screening has not been completed or if the results give cause for doubt or concern?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"customer_response":"For External - See Richard Jenkins.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","question":"Does the agreement with the third party clearly specify all responsibilities and notification procedures for screening?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"customer_response":"See Sean Wilkins","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","question":"Is the information on all candidates being considered for positions within the organization collected and handled in accordance with any appropriate legislation existing in the relevant jurisdiction?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Screening","policy_defined":{"id":3,"text":"Written Policy","value":0.75},"question":"Depending on applicable legislation, are the candidates informed beforehand about the screening activities?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Users sign an NDA that covers infosec requirements.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Terms and conditions of employment","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"As part of their contractual obligation, do employees, contractors and third party users agree and sign the terms and conditions of their employment contract, which states their and the organization‟s responsibilities for information security?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Terms and conditions of employment","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Do the terms and conditions of employment reflect the organization‟s security policy in addition to clarifying and stating:&#10;a) that all employees, contractors and third party users who are given access to sensitive information are required to sign a confidentiality or non-disclosure agreement prior to being given access to information processing facilities;&#10;b) the employee‟s, contractor‟s and any other user‟s legal responsibilities and rights, e.g. regarding copyright laws or data protection legislation;&#10;c) responsibilities for the classification of information and management of organizational assets associated with information systems and services handled by the employee, contractor or third party user;&#10;d) responsibilities of the employee, contractor or third party user for the handling of information received from other companies or external parties;&#10;e) responsibilities of the organization for the handling of personal information, including personal information created as a result of, or in the course of, employment with the organization;&#10;f) responsibilities that are extended outside the organization‟s premises and outside normal working hours, e.g. in the case of home-working;&#10;g) actions to be taken if the employee, contractor or third party user disregards the organization‟s security requirements?Do the terms and conditions of employment reflect the organization‟s security policy in addition to clarifying and stating:&#10;a) that all employees, contractors and third party users who are given access to sensitive information are required to sign a confidentiality or non-disclosure agreement prior to being given access to information processing facilities;&#10;b) the employee‟s, contractor‟s and any other user‟s legal responsibilities and rights, e.g. regarding copyright laws or data protection legislation;&#10;c) responsibilities for the classification of information and management of organizational assets associated with information systems and services handled by the employee, contractor or third party user;&#10;d) responsibilities of the employee, contractor or third party user for the handling of information received from other companies or external parties;&#10;e) responsibilities of the organization for the handling of personal information, including personal information created as a result of, or in the course of, employment with the organization;&#10;f) responsibilities that are extended outside the organization‟s premises and outside normal working hours, e.g. in the case of home-working;&#10;g) actions to be taken if the employee, contractor or third party user disregards the organization‟s security requirements?Do the terms and conditions of employment reflect the organization‟s security policy in addition to clarifying and stating:&#10;a) that all employees, contractors and third party users who are given access to sensitive information are required to sign a confidentiality or non-disclosure agreement prior to being given access to information processing facilities;&#10;b) the employee‟s, contractor‟s and any other user‟s legal responsibilities and rights, e.g. regarding copyright laws or data protection legislation;&#10;c) responsibilities for the classification of information and management of organizational assets associated with information systems and services handled by the employee, contractor or third party user;&#10;d) responsibilities of the employee, contractor or third party user for the handling of information received from other companies or external parties;&#10;e) responsibilities of the organization for the handling of personal information, including personal information created as a result of, or in the course of, employment with the organization;&#10;f) responsibilities that are extended outside the organization‟s premises and outside normal working hours, e.g. in the case of home-working;&#10;g) actions to be taken if the employee, contractor or third party user disregards the organization‟s security requirements?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cannot start employment without signing the NDA, which covers Information Security.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Terms and conditions of employment","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization ensure that employees, contractors and third party users agree to terms and conditions concerning information security appropriate to the nature and extent of access they will have to the organization‟s assets associated with information systems and services?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Non-compete agreement is signed.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Terms and conditions of employment","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization ensure that where appropriate, responsibilities contained within the terms and conditions of employment continue for a defined period after the end of the employment?","reason":"Security responsibilities should be addressed prior to employment in adequate job descriptions and in terms and conditions of employment. All candidates for employment, contractors and third party users should be adequately screened, especially for sensitive jobs. Employees, contractors and third party users of information processing facilities should sign an agreement on their security roles and responsibilities.","section":"Prior to employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Management Responsibilities","question":"Does management require employees, contractors and third party users to apply security in accordance with established policies and procedures of the organization?","reason":"Management responsibilities should be defined to ensure that security is applied throughout an individual‟s employment within the organization. An adequate level of awareness, education, and training in security procedures and the correct use of information processing facilities should be provided to all employees, contractors and third party users to minimize possible security risks. A formal disciplinary process for handling security breaches should be established.","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Covered in the employee handbook.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Management Responsibilities","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does management‟s responsibilities include ensuring that employees, contractors and third party users:&#10;a) are properly briefed on their information security roles and responsibilities prior to being granted access to sensitive information or information systems;&#10;b) are provided with guidelines to state security expectations of their role within the organization;&#10;c) are motivated to fulfill the security policies of the organization;&#10;d) achieve a level of awareness on security relevant to their roles and responsibilities within the organization;&#10;e) conform to the terms and conditions of employment, which includes the organization‟s information security policy and appropriate methods of working;&#10;f) continue to have the appropriate skills and qualifications?Does management‟s responsibilities include ensuring that employees, contractors and third party users:&#10;a) are properly briefed on their information security roles and responsibilities prior to being granted access to sensitive information or information systems;&#10;b) are provided with guidelines to state security expectations of their role within the organization;&#10;c) are motivated to fulfill the security policies of the organization;&#10;d) achieve a level of awareness on security relevant to their roles and responsibilities within the organization;&#10;e) conform to the terms and conditions of employment, which includes the organization‟s information security policy and appropriate methods of working;&#10;f) continue to have the appropriate skills and qualifications?","reason":"Management responsibilities should be defined to ensure that security is applied throughout an individual‟s employment within the organization. An adequate level of awareness, education, and training in security procedures and the correct use of information processing facilities should be provided to all employees, contractors and third party users to minimize possible security risks. A formal disciplinary process for handling security breaches should be established.","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Kayla Webb - Unsure if this is written into policy, but is managed at the team level\r\n\r\nCristi Leone - No","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Information security awareness, education and training","question":"Do all employees of the organization and, where relevant, contractors and third party users receive appropriate awareness training and regular updates in organizational policies and procedures, as relevant for their job function?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Kayla Webb - done by teams / managers; Not at the corporate level.\r\n\r\nCristi Leone -","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Information security awareness, education and training","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Does awareness training commence with a formal induction process designed to introduce the organization‟s security policies and expectations before access to information or services is granted?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Kayla Webb - Covered in monthly training.&#10;&#10;Cristi Leone - No","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Information security awareness, education and training","question":"Does ongoing training include security requirements, legal responsibilities and business controls, as well as training in the correct use of information processing facilities e.g. log-on procedure, use of software packages and information on the disciplinary process?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Kayla Webb - Done at the team level.&#10;&#10;Cristi Leone - No","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Information security awareness, education and training","question":"Are the security awareness, education, and training activities suitable and relevant to the person‟s role, responsibilities and skills?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Cristi Leone - no.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Information security awareness, education and training","question":"Do the security awareness, education, and training activities include information on known threats, who to contact for further security advice and the proper channels for reporting information security incidents?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Employee Security Risk Assessment","question":"Does management evaluate the effectiveness of the security policy and security awareness training through the use of simulated tests (social engineering, phishing emails, malicious SMS/text messages, infected/unauthorized portable storage devices, etc…)? ","section":"During employment","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Covered in the Employee handbook.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Disciplinary process","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Is there a formal disciplinary process for employees who have committed a security breach?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - Approached by legal on multiple occasions to verify breaches","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Disciplinary process","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Does the organization ensure that the disciplinary process does not commence without prior verification that a security breach has occurred?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Depends on the severity of the incident.   Level of corrective actions are covered in the Employee Handbook.  Pg 36.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Disciplinary process","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the formal disciplinary process ensure correct and fair treatment for employees who are suspected of committing breaches of security?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Depends on the severity of the incident.   Level of corrective actions are covered in the Employee Handbook.  Pg 36.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Disciplinary process","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the formal disciplinary process provide for a graduated response that takes into consideration factors such as the nature and gravity of the breach and its impact on business, whether or not this is a first or repeat offense, whether or not the violator was properly trained, relevant legislation, business contracts and other factors as required?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Covered in the Employee Handbook.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Disciplinary process","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"In serious cases of misconduct does the process allow for instant removal of duties, access rights and privileges, and for immediate escorting out of the site, if necessary?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Yes.&#10;&#10;The following is a partial list of corrective actions that may be used:&#10; Informal or Formal Coaching&#10; Verbal Reprimand&#10; Written Reprimand&#10; Performance Improvement Plan (PIP)&#10; Corrective Action Notice&#10; Suspension&#10; Demotion or Transfer&#10; Reduction in Pay&#10; Termination","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Disciplinary process","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Is the disciplinary process also used as a deterrent to prevent employees, contractors and third party users from violating organizational security policies and procedures, and any other security breaches?","section":"During employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Written, not signed, policies cover this. &#10;&#10;Termination Process  7  14  16 (external and internal).docx&#10;Terminating In Pay Com.docx","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Termination responsibilities","policy_defined":{"id":3,"text":"Written Policy","value":0.75},"question":"Are responsibilities for performing employment termination or change of employment clearly defined and assigned?","reason":"Responsibilities should be in place to ensure an employee‟s, contractor‟s or third party user‟s exit from the organization is managed, and that the return of all equipment and the removal of all access rights are completed.","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera - Termination notice is sent to appropriate groups.   For Non-compete clauses - legal is engaged if someone is breaking their contract.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Termination responsibilities","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the communication of termination responsibilities include ongoing security requirements and legal responsibilities and, where appropriate, responsibilities contained within any confidentiality agreement, and the terms and conditions of employment continuing for a defined period after the end of the employee‟s, contractor‟s or third party user‟s employment?","reason":"Responsibilities should be in place to ensure an employee‟s, contractor‟s or third party user‟s exit from the organization is managed, and that the return of all equipment and the removal of all access rights are completed.","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Termination responsibilities","question":"Are responsibilities and duties still valid after termination of employment contained in employee‟s, contractor‟s or third party user‟s contracts?","reason":"Responsibilities should be in place to ensure an employee‟s, contractor‟s or third party user‟s exit from the organization is managed, and that the return of all equipment and the removal of all access rights are completed.","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Termination responsibilities","question":"Are changes of responsibility or employment managed as the termination of the respective responsibility or employment, and the new responsibility or employment controlled as described in step 8.1 above?","reason":"Responsibilities should be in place to ensure an employee‟s, contractor‟s or third party user‟s exit from the organization is managed, and that the return of all equipment and the removal of all access rights are completed.","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - The Manager is responsible for collecting and returning assets to the IT Department.   See Separation Notice Policy and page 17 of the Employee handbook.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Return of assets","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Do all employees, contractors and third party users return all of the organization‟s assets in their possession upon termination of their employment, contract or agreement?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - The Manager is responsible for collecting and returning assets to the IT Department.   See Separation Notice Policy and page 17 of the Employee handbook.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Return of assets","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Is the termination process formalized to include the return of all previously issued software, corporate documents, and equipment, including other organizational assets such as mobile computing devices, credit cards, access cards, software, manuals, and information stored on electronic media?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - No personal laptops allowed.  Only Personal phones.   Hard drives are sent Iron Mountain.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Return of assets","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Are procedures followed to ensure that all relevant information is transferred to the organization and securely erased from the equipment in cases where an employee, contractor or third party user purchases the organization‟s equipment or uses their own personal equipment?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"customer_response":"Not 100% of the time","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Return of assets","question":"In cases where an employee, contractor or third party user has knowledge that is important to ongoing operations, is that information documented and transferred to the organization?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":4,"text":"Automated on All Systems","value":1},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Letter of Separation must be signed prior to initiating removal of access rights.&#10;&#10;Tracked through email comms.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Removal of access rights","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are the access rights of all employees, contractors and third party users to information and information processing facilities removed upon termination of their employment, contract or agreement, or adjusted upon change?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Removal of access rights","question":"Upon termination, are the access rights of an individual to assets associated with information systems and services reconsidered?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Removal of access rights","question":"Do changes of an employment reflect in removal of all access rights that were not approved for the new employment?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Kiera Wood - Separation Notice Form covers all items to be returned.   &#10;&#10;The Manager completes the employee termination checklist.","domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Removal of access rights","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Do the access rights to be removed or adapted include physical and logical access, keys, identification cards, information processing facilities, subscriptions, and removal from any documentation that identifies them as a current member of the organization?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Removal of access rights","question":"Are passwords for accounts remaining active which are known by a departing employee, contractor or third party user changed upon termination or change of employment, contract or agreement?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Removal of access rights","question":"Are access rights for information assets and information processing facilities reduced or removed before the employment terminates or changes, depending on the evaluation of risk factors such as:&#10;a) whether the termination or change is initiated by the employee, contractor or third party user, or by management and the reason of termination;&#10;b) the current responsibilities of the employee, contractor or any other user;&#10;c) the value of the assets currently accessible?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"domain":"Human Resources Security","objective":"Removal of access rights","question":"In circumstances where access rights may be allocated on the basis of being available to more people than the departing employee, contractor or third party user, e.g. group IDs, is the departing individuals removed from any group access lists and are arrangements made to advise all other employees, contractors and third party users involved to no longer share this information with the person departing?","section":"Termination or change of employment","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Physical security perimeter","question":"Are security perimeters (barriers such as walls, card controlled entry gates or manned reception desks) used to protect areas that contain information and information processing facilities?","reason":"Critical or sensitive information processing facilities should be housed in secure areas, protected by defined security perimeters, with appropriate security barriers and entry controls. They should be physically protected from unauthorized access, damage, and interference. The protection provided should be commensurate with the identified risks.","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Physical security perimeter","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for physical security perimeters:&#10;a) security perimeters should be clearly defined, and the siting and strength of each of the perimeters should depend on the security requirements of the assets within the perimeter and the results of a risk assessment;&#10;b) perimeters of a building or site containing information processing facilities should be physically sound (i.e. there should be no gaps in the perimeter or areas where a break-in could easily occur); the external walls of the site should be of solid construction and all external doors should be suitably protected against unauthorized access with control mechanisms, e.g. bars, alarms, locks etc; doors and windows should be locked when unattended and external protection should be considered for windows, particularly at ground level;&#10;c) a manned reception area or other means to control physical access to the site or building should be in place; access to sites and buildings should be restricted to authorized personnel only;&#10;d) physical barriers should, where applicable, be built to prevent unauthorized physical access and environmental contamination;&#10;e) all fire doors on a security perimeter should be alarmed, monitored, and tested in conjunction with the walls to establish the required level of resistance in accordance to suitable regional, national, and international standards; they should operate in accordance with local fire code in a fail-safe manner;&#10;f) suitable intruder detection systems should be installed to national, regional or international standards and regularly tested to cover all external doors and accessible windows; unoccupied areas should be alarmed at all times; cover should also be provided for other areas, e.g. computer room or communications rooms;&#10;g) information processing facilities managed by the organization should be physically separated from those managed by third parties?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for physical security perimeters:&#10;a) security perimeters should be clearly defined, and the siting and strength of each of the perimeters should depend on the security requirements of the assets within the perimeter and the results of a risk assessment;&#10;b) perimeters of a building or site containing information processing facilities should be physically sound (i.e. there should be no gaps in the perimeter or areas where a break-in could easily occur); the external walls of the site should be of solid construction and all external doors should be suitably protected against unauthorized access with control mechanisms, e.g. bars, alarms, locks etc; doors and windows should be locked when unattended and external protection should be considered for windows, particularly at ground level;&#10;c) a manned reception area or other means to control physical access to the site or building should be in place; access to sites and buildings should be restricted to authorized personnel only;&#10;d) physical barriers should, where applicable, be built to prevent unauthorized physical access and environmental contamination;&#10;e) all fire doors on a security perimeter should be alarmed, monitored, and tested in conjunction with the walls to establish the required level of resistance in accordance to suitable regional, national, and international standards; they should operate in accordance with local fire code in a fail-safe manner;&#10;f) suitable intruder detection systems should be installed to national, regional or international standards and regularly tested to cover all external doors and accessible windows; unoccupied areas should be alarmed at all times; cover should also be provided for other areas, e.g. computer room or communications rooms;&#10;g) information processing facilities managed by the organization should be physically separated from those managed by third parties?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for physical security perimeters:&#10;a) security perimeters should be clearly defined, and the siting and strength of each of the perimeters should depend on the security requirements of the assets within the perimeter and the results of a risk assessment;&#10;b) perimeters of a building or site containing information processing facilities should be physically sound (i.e. there should be no gaps in the perimeter or areas where a break-in could easily occur); the external walls of the site should be of solid construction and all external doors should be suitably protected against unauthorized access with control mechanisms, e.g. bars, alarms, locks etc; doors and windows should be locked when unattended and external protection should be considered for windows, particularly at ground level;&#10;c) a manned reception area or other means to control physical access to the site or building should be in place; access to sites and buildings should be restricted to authorized personnel only;&#10;d) physical barriers should, where applicable, be built to prevent unauthorized physical access and environmental contamination;&#10;e) all fire doors on a security perimeter should be alarmed, monitored, and tested in conjunction with the walls to establish the required level of resistance in accordance to suitable regional, national, and international standards; they should operate in accordance with local fire code in a fail-safe manner;&#10;f) suitable intruder detection systems should be installed to national, regional or international standards and regularly tested to cover all external doors and accessible windows; unoccupied areas should be alarmed at all times; cover should also be provided for other areas, e.g. computer room or communications rooms;&#10;g) information processing facilities managed by the organization should be physically separated from those managed by third parties?","reason":"Critical or sensitive information processing facilities should be housed in secure areas, protected by defined security perimeters, with appropriate security barriers and entry controls. They should be physically protected from unauthorized access, damage, and interference. The protection provided should be commensurate with the identified risks.","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"","domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Physical security perimeter","question":"Is special consideration towards physical access security given to buildings where multiple organizations are housed?","reason":"Critical or sensitive information processing facilities should be housed in secure areas, protected by defined security perimeters, with appropriate security barriers and entry controls. They should be physically protected from unauthorized access, damage, and interference. The protection provided should be commensurate with the identified risks.","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Physical entry controls","question":"Are secure areas protected by appropriate entry controls to ensure that only authorized personnel are allowed access?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Physical entry controls","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for physical entry controls:&#10;a) the date and time of entry and departure of visitors should be recorded, and all visitors should be supervised unless their access has been previously approved; they should only be granted access for specific, authorized purposes and should be issued with instructions on the security requirements of the area and on emergency procedures.&#10;b) access to areas where sensitive information is processed or stored should be controlled and restricted to authorized persons only; authentication controls, e.g. access control card plus PIN, should be used to authorize and validate all access; an audit trail of all access should be securely maintained;&#10;c) all employees, contractors and third party users and all visitors should be required to wear some form of visible identification and should immediately notify security personnel if they encounter unescorted visitors and anyone not wearing visible identification;&#10;d) third party support service personnel should be granted restricted access to secure areas or sensitive information processing facilities only when required; this access should be authorized and monitored;&#10;e) access rights to secure areas should be regularly reviewed and updated, and revoked when necessary?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for physical entry controls:&#10;a) the date and time of entry and departure of visitors should be recorded, and all visitors should be supervised unless their access has been previously approved; they should only be granted access for specific, authorized purposes and should be issued with instructions on the security requirements of the area and on emergency procedures.&#10;b) access to areas where sensitive information is processed or stored should be controlled and restricted to authorized persons only; authentication controls, e.g. access control card plus PIN, should be used to authorize and validate all access; an audit trail of all access should be securely maintained;&#10;c) all employees, contractors and third party users and all visitors should be required to wear some form of visible identification and should immediately notify security personnel if they encounter unescorted visitors and anyone not wearing visible identification;&#10;d) third party support service personnel should be granted restricted access to secure areas or sensitive information processing facilities only when required; this access should be authorized and monitored;&#10;e) access rights to secure areas should be regularly reviewed and updated, and revoked when necessary?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for physical entry controls:&#10;a) the date and time of entry and departure of visitors should be recorded, and all visitors should be supervised unless their access has been previously approved; they should only be granted access for specific, authorized purposes and should be issued with instructions on the security requirements of the area and on emergency procedures.&#10;b) access to areas where sensitive information is processed or stored should be controlled and restricted to authorized persons only; authentication controls, e.g. access control card plus PIN, should be used to authorize and validate all access; an audit trail of all access should be securely maintained;&#10;c) all employees, contractors and third party users and all visitors should be required to wear some form of visible identification and should immediately notify security personnel if they encounter unescorted visitors and anyone not wearing visible identification;&#10;d) third party support service personnel should be granted restricted access to secure areas or sensitive information processing facilities only when required; this access should be authorized and monitored;&#10;e) access rights to secure areas should be regularly reviewed and updated, and revoked when necessary?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Securing offices, rooms and facilities","question":"Is physical security for offices, rooms, and facilities designed and applied?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Securing offices, rooms and facilities","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for securing offices, rooms, and facilities:&#10;a) account should be taken of relevant health and safety regulations and standards;&#10;b) key facilities should be sited to avoid access by the public;&#10;c) where applicable, buildings should be unobtrusive and give minimum indication of their purpose, with no obvious signs, outside or inside the building identifying the presence of information processing activities;&#10;d) directories and internal telephone books identifying locations of sensitive information processing facilities should not be readily accessible by the public. consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for securing offices, rooms, and facilities:&#10;a) account should be taken of relevant health and safety regulations and standards;&#10;b) key facilities should be sited to avoid access by the public;&#10;c) where applicable, buildings should be unobtrusive and give minimum indication of their purpose, with no obvious signs, outside or inside the building identifying the presence of information processing activities;&#10;d) directories and internal telephone books identifying locations of sensitive information processing facilities should not be readily accessible by the public. Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for securing offices, rooms, and facilities:&#10;a) account should be taken of relevant health and safety regulations and standards;&#10;b) key facilities should be sited to avoid access by the public;&#10;c) where applicable, buildings should be unobtrusive and give minimum indication of their purpose, with no obvious signs, outside or inside the building identifying the presence of information processing activities;&#10;d) directories and internal telephone books identifying locations of sensitive information processing facilities should not be readily accessible by the public.","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Protecting against external and environmental threats","question":"Is physical protection against damage from fire, flood, earthquake, explosion, civil unrest, and other forms of natural or man-made disaster designed and applied?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Protecting against external and environmental threats","question":"Is consideration given to any security threats presented by neighboring premises, e.g. a fire in a neighboring building, water leaking from the roof or in floors below ground level or an explosion in the street?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Protecting against external and environmental threats","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate to avoid damage from fire, flood, earthquake, explosion, civil unrest, and other forms of natural or man-made disaster:&#10;a) hazardous or combustible materials should be stored at a safe distance from a secure area. Bulk supplies such as stationery should not be stored within a secure area;&#10;b) fallback equipment and back-up media should be sited at a safe distance to avoid damage from a disaster affecting the main site;&#10;c) appropriate firefighting equipment should be provided and suitably placed?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate to avoid damage from fire, flood, earthquake, explosion, civil unrest, and other forms of natural or man-made disaster:&#10;a) hazardous or combustible materials should be stored at a safe distance from a secure area. Bulk supplies such as stationery should not be stored within a secure area;&#10;b) fallback equipment and back-up media should be sited at a safe distance to avoid damage from a disaster affecting the main site;&#10;c) appropriate firefighting equipment should be provided and suitably placed?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate to avoid damage from fire, flood, earthquake, explosion, civil unrest, and other forms of natural or man-made disaster:&#10;a) hazardous or combustible materials should be stored at a safe distance from a secure area. Bulk supplies such as stationery should not be stored within a secure area;&#10;b) fallback equipment and back-up media should be sited at a safe distance to avoid damage from a disaster affecting the main site;&#10;c) appropriate firefighting equipment should be provided and suitably placed?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Working in secure areas","question":"Is physical protection and guidelines for working in secure areas designed and applied?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Working in secure areas","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate:&#10;a) personnel should only be aware of the existence of, or activities within, a secure area on a need to know basis;&#10;b) unsupervised working in secure areas should be avoided both for safety reasons and to prevent opportunities for malicious activities;&#10;c) vacant secure areas should be physically locked and periodically checked;&#10;d) photographic, video, audio or other recording equipment, such as cameras in mobile devices, should not be allowed, unless authorized?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate:&#10;a) personnel should only be aware of the existence of, or activities within, a secure area on a need to know basis;&#10;b) unsupervised working in secure areas should be avoided both for safety reasons and to prevent opportunities for malicious activities;&#10;c) vacant secure areas should be physically locked and periodically checked;&#10;d) photographic, video, audio or other recording equipment, such as cameras in mobile devices, should not be allowed, unless authorized?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate:&#10;a) personnel should only be aware of the existence of, or activities within, a secure area on a need to know basis;&#10;b) unsupervised working in secure areas should be avoided both for safety reasons and to prevent opportunities for malicious activities;&#10;c) vacant secure areas should be physically locked and periodically checked;&#10;d) photographic, video, audio or other recording equipment, such as cameras in mobile devices, should not be allowed, unless authorized?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"A staffed loading area with a camera is in place.","domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Public access delivery and loading areas","question":"Are access points such as delivery and loading areas and other points where unauthorized persons may enter the premises controlled and, if possible, isolated from information processing facilities to avoid unauthorized access?","section":"Secure areas","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Comms equipment is secured.  No UPS in place though.","control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Equipment siting and protection","question":"Is sensitive and/or mission critical equipment sited or protected to reduce the risks from environmental threats and hazards, and opportunities for unauthorized access?","reason":"Equipment should be protected from physical and environmental threats. Protection of equipment (including that used off-site, and the removal of property) is necessary to reduce the risk of unauthorized access to information and to protect against loss or damage. This should also consider equipment siting and disposal. Special controls may be required to protect against physical threats, and to safeguard supporting facilities, such as the electrical supply and cabling infrastructure.","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Equipment siting and protection","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for protect equipment:&#10;a) equipment should be sited to minimize unnecessary access into work areas;&#10;b) information processing facilities handling sensitive data should be positioned and the viewing angle restricted to reduce the risk of information being viewed by unauthorized persons during their use, and storage facilities secured to avoid unauthorized access;&#10;c) items requiring special protection should be isolated to reduce the general level of protection required;&#10;d) controls should be adopted to minimize the risk of potential physical threats, e.g. theft, fire, explosives, smoke, water (or water supply failure), dust, vibration, chemical effects, electrical supply interference, communications interference, electromagnetic radiation,&#10;and vandalism;&#10;e) guidelines for eating, drinking, and smoking in proximity to information processing facilities should be established;&#10;f) environmental conditions, such as temperature and humidity, should be monitored for conditions, which could adversely affect the operation of information processing facilities;&#10;g) lightning protection should be applied to all buildings and lightning protection filters should be fitted to all incoming power and communications lines;&#10;h) the use of special protection methods, such as keyboard membranes, should be considered for equipment in industrial environments;&#10;i) equipment processing sensitive information should be protected to minimize the risk of information leakage due to emanation?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for protect equipment:&#10;a) equipment should be sited to minimize unnecessary access into work areas;&#10;b) information processing facilities handling sensitive data should be positioned and the viewing angle restricted to reduce the risk of information being viewed by unauthorized persons during their use, and storage facilities secured to avoid unauthorized access;&#10;c) items requiring special protection should be isolated to reduce the general level of protection required;&#10;d) controls should be adopted to minimize the risk of potential physical threats, e.g. theft, fire, explosives, smoke, water (or water supply failure), dust, vibration, chemical effects, electrical supply interference, communications interference, electromagnetic radiation,&#10;and vandalism;&#10;e) guidelines for eating, drinking, and smoking in proximity to information processing facilities should be established;&#10;f) environmental conditions, such as temperature and humidity, should be monitored for conditions, which could adversely affect the operation of information processing facilities;&#10;g) lightning protection should be applied to all buildings and lightning protection filters should be fitted to all incoming power and communications lines;&#10;h) the use of special protection methods, such as keyboard membranes, should be considered for equipment in industrial environments;&#10;i) equipment processing sensitive information should be protected to minimize the risk of information leakage due to emanation?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for protect equipment:&#10;a) equipment should be sited to minimize unnecessary access into work areas;&#10;b) information processing facilities handling sensitive data should be positioned and the viewing angle restricted to reduce the risk of information being viewed by unauthorized persons during their use, and storage facilities secured to avoid unauthorized access;&#10;c) items requiring special protection should be isolated to reduce the general level of protection required;&#10;d) controls should be adopted to minimize the risk of potential physical threats, e.g. theft, fire, explosives, smoke, water (or water supply failure), dust, vibration, chemical effects, electrical supply interference, communications interference, electromagnetic radiation,&#10;and vandalism;&#10;e) guidelines for eating, drinking, and smoking in proximity to information processing facilities should be established;&#10;f) environmental conditions, such as temperature and humidity, should be monitored for conditions, which could adversely affect the operation of information processing facilities;&#10;g) lightning protection should be applied to all buildings and lightning protection filters should be fitted to all incoming power and communications lines;&#10;h) the use of special protection methods, such as keyboard membranes, should be considered for equipment in industrial environments;&#10;i) equipment processing sensitive information should be protected to minimize the risk of information leakage due to emanation?","reason":"Equipment should be protected from physical and environmental threats. Protection of equipment (including that used off-site, and the removal of property) is necessary to reduce the risk of unauthorized access to information and to protect against loss or damage. This should also consider equipment siting and disposal. Special controls may be required to protect against physical threats, and to safeguard supporting facilities, such as the electrical supply and cabling infrastructure.","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"UPS not deployed, generator is deployed.","control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is equipment protected from power failures and other disruptions caused by failures in supporting utilities?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"","control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is all supporting utilities, such as electricity, water supply, sewage, heating/ventilation, and air conditioning adequate for the systems they are supporting?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":18.75},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Are support utilities regularly inspected and as appropriate tested to ensure their proper functioning and to reduce any risk from their malfunction or failure?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is a suitable electrical supply provided that conforms to the equipment manufacturer‟s specifications?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Do power contingency plans cover the action to be taken on failure of the UPS?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Was a back-up generator considered if processing is required to continue in case of a prolonged power failure?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Tested weekly.  Generator always has 50% fuel.","domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is an adequate supply of fuel available to ensure that the generator can perform for a prolonged period?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Are UPS equipment and generators regularly checked to ensure it has adequate capacity and is tested in accordance with the manufacturer‟s recommendations?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Are emergency power off switches located near emergency exits in equipment rooms to facilitate rapid power down in case of an emergency?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is emergency lighting provided in case of main power failure?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is the water supply stable and adequate to supply air conditioning, humidification equipment and fire suppression systems?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is an alarm system to detect malfunctions in the supporting utilities evaluated and installed if required?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"","domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Is telecommunications equipment connected to the utility provider by at least two diverse routes to prevent failure in one connection path removing voice services?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Supporting utilities","question":"Are voice services adequate to meet local legal requirements for emergency communications?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Cabling security","question":"Is power and telecommunications cabling carrying data or supporting information services protected from interception or damage?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Cabling security","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for cabling security:&#10;a) power and telecommunications lines into information processing facilities should be underground, where possible, or subject to adequate alternative protection;&#10;b) network cabling should be protected from unauthorized interception or damage, for example by using a conduit or by avoiding routes through public areas;&#10;c) power cables should be segregated from communications cables to prevent interference;&#10;d) clearly identifiable cable and equipment markings should be used to minimize handling errors, such as accidental patching of wrong network cables;&#10;e) a documented patch list should be used to reduce the possibility of errors;&#10;f) for sensitive or critical systems further controls to consider include:&#10;1) installation of armored conduit and locked rooms or boxes at inspection and termination points;&#10;2) use of alternative routing and/or transmission media providing appropriate security;&#10;3) use of fiber optic cabling;&#10;4) use of electromagnetic shielding to protect the cables;&#10;5) initiation of technical sweeps and physical inspections for unauthorized devices being attached to the cables;&#10;6) controlled access to patch panels and cable rooms?Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for cabling security:&#10;a) power and telecommunications lines into information processing facilities should be underground, where possible, or subject to adequate alternative protection;&#10;b) network cabling should be protected from unauthorized interception or damage, for example by using a conduit or by avoiding routes through public areas;&#10;c) power cables should be segregated from communications cables to prevent interference;&#10;d) clearly identifiable cable and equipment markings should be used to minimize handling errors, such as accidental patching of wrong network cables;&#10;e) a documented patch list should be used to reduce the possibility of errors;&#10;f) for sensitive or critical systems further controls to consider include:&#10;1) installation of armored conduit and locked rooms or boxes at inspection and termination points;&#10;2) use of alternative routing and/or transmission media providing appropriate security;&#10;3) use of fiber optic cabling;&#10;4) use of electromagnetic shielding to protect the cables;&#10;5) initiation of technical sweeps and physical inspections for unauthorized devices being attached to the cables;&#10;6) controlled access to patch panels and cable rooms?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Equipment Maintenance","question":"Is equipment correctly maintained to ensure its continued availability and integrity?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Equipment Maintenance","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for equipment maintenance:&#10;a) equipment should be maintained in accordance with the supplier‟s recommended service intervals and specifications;&#10;b) only authorized maintenance personnel should carry out repairs and service equipment;&#10;c) records should be kept of all suspected or actual faults, and all preventive and corrective maintenance;&#10;d) appropriate controls should be implemented when equipment is scheduled for maintenance, taking into account whether this maintenance is performed by personnel on site or external to the organization; where necessary, sensitive information should be cleared from the equipment, or the maintenance personnel should be sufficiently cleared;&#10;e) all requirements imposed by insurance policies should be complied with?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Securing of equipment off-premises","question":"Is security applied to off-site equipment taking into account the different risks of working outside the organization‟s premises?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Securing of equipment off-premises","question":"Regardless of ownership, is the use of any information processing equipment outside the organization‟s premises authorized by management?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Securing of equipment off-premises","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for the protection of off-site equipment:&#10;a) equipment and media taken off the premises should not be left unattended in public places; portable computers should be carried as hand luggage and disguised where possible when traveling;&#10;b) manufacturers‟ instructions for protecting equipment should be observed at all times, e.g. protection against exposure to strong electromagnetic fields;&#10;c) home-working controls should be determined by a risk assessment and suitable controls applied as appropriate, e.g. lockable filing cabinets, clear desk policy, access controls for computers and secure communication with the office;&#10;d) adequate insurance coverage should be in place to protect equipment off-site?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Securing of equipment off-premises","question":"Are security risks, e.g. of damage, theft or eavesdropping, which may vary considerably between locations, taken into account in determining the most appropriate controls?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Secure disposal or re-use of equipment","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Are all items of equipment containing storage media checked to ensure that any sensitive data and licensed software has been removed or securely overwritten prior to disposal?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Secure disposal or re-use of equipment","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Are devices containing sensitive information physically destroyed or the information destroyed, deleted or overwritten using techniques to make the original information non-retrievable rather than using the standard delete or format function?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Secure disposal or re-use of equipment","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Are damaged devices containing sensitive data subjected to a risk assessment to determine whether the items are physically destroyed rather than sent for repair or discarded?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Removal of property","question":"Is equipment, information or software restricted from being taken off-site without prior authorization?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Removal of property","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for the removal of property:&#10;a) equipment, information or software should not be taken off-site without prior authorization;&#10;b) employees, contractors and third party users who have authority to permit off-site removal of assets should be clearly identified;&#10;c) time limits for equipment removal should be set and returns checked for compliance;&#10;d) where necessary and appropriate, equipment should be recorded as being removed off-site and recorded when returned?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Removal of property","question":"Are spot checks, undertaken to detect unauthorized removal of property, to detect unauthorized recording devices, weapons, etc., and prevent their entry into the site carried out in accordance with relevant legislation and regulations?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Removal of property","question":"Are individuals made aware if spot checks are carried out?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Physical and Environmental Security","objective":"Removal of property","question":"Are the spot checks only performed with authorization appropriate for the legal and regulatory requirements?","section":"Equipment security","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"SOPs were available on the internal SharePoint website.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Documented Operating procedures","question":"Are operating procedures documented, maintained, and made available to all users who need them?","reason":"Responsibilities and procedures for the management and operation of all information processing facilities should be established. This includes the development of appropriate operating procedures. Segregation of duties should be implemented, where appropriate, to reduce the risk of negligent or deliberate system misuse.","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No emergency startup/shutdown procedures.  No backup/restore procedures.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Documented Operating procedures","question":"Are documented procedures prepared for system activities associated with information processing and communication facilities, such as computer start-up and close-down procedures, backup, equipment maintenance, media handling, computer room and mail handling management, and safety?","reason":"Responsibilities and procedures for the management and operation of all information processing facilities should be established. This includes the development of appropriate operating procedures. Segregation of duties should be implemented, where appropriate, to reduce the risk of negligent or deliberate system misuse.","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Too long of a question to be conducted during an audit.  Consider removal or separating into different questions.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Documented Operating procedures","question":"Do the operating procedures specify the instructions for the detailed execution of each job including:&#10;a) processing and handling of information;&#10;b) backup;&#10;c) scheduling requirements, including inter-dependencies with other systems, earliest job start and latest job completion times;&#10;d) instructions for handling errors or other exceptional conditions, which might arise during job execution, including restrictions on the use of system utilities;&#10;e) support contacts in the event of unexpected operational or technical difficulties;&#10;f) special output and media handling instructions, such as the use of special stationery or the management of confidential output including procedures for secure disposal of output from failed jobs;&#10;g) system restart and recovery procedures for use in the event of system failure;&#10;h) the management of audit-trail and system log information?Do the operating procedures specify the instructions for the detailed execution of each job including:&#10;a) processing and handling of information;&#10;b) backup;&#10;c) scheduling requirements, including inter-dependencies with other systems, earliest job start and latest job completion times;&#10;d) instructions for handling errors or other exceptional conditions, which might arise during job execution, including restrictions on the use of system utilities;&#10;e) support contacts in the event of unexpected operational or technical difficulties;&#10;f) special output and media handling instructions, such as the use of special stationery or the management of confidential output including procedures for secure disposal of output from failed jobs;&#10;g) system restart and recovery procedures for use in the event of system failure;&#10;h) the management of audit-trail and system log information?Do the operating procedures specify the instructions for the detailed execution of each job including:&#10;a) processing and handling of information;&#10;b) backup;&#10;c) scheduling requirements, including inter-dependencies with other systems, earliest job start and latest job completion times;&#10;d) instructions for handling errors or other exceptional conditions, which might arise during job execution, including restrictions on the use of system utilities;&#10;e) support contacts in the event of unexpected operational or technical difficulties;&#10;f) special output and media handling instructions, such as the use of special stationery or the management of confidential output including procedures for secure disposal of output from failed jobs;&#10;g) system restart and recovery procedures for use in the event of system failure;&#10;h) the management of audit-trail and system log information?Do the operating procedures specify the instructions for the detailed execution of each job including:&#10;a) processing and handling of information;&#10;b) backup;&#10;c) scheduling requirements, including inter-dependencies with other systems, earliest job start and latest job completion times;&#10;d) instructions for handling errors or other exceptional conditions, which might arise during job execution, including restrictions on the use of system utilities;&#10;e) support contacts in the event of unexpected operational or technical difficulties;&#10;f) special output and media handling instructions, such as the use of special stationery or the management of confidential output including procedures for secure disposal of output from failed jobs;&#10;g) system restart and recovery procedures for use in the event of system failure;&#10;h) the management of audit-trail and system log information?","reason":"Responsibilities and procedures for the management and operation of all information processing facilities should be established. This includes the development of appropriate operating procedures. Segregation of duties should be implemented, where appropriate, to reduce the risk of negligent or deliberate system misuse.","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Formal review process in place.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Documented Operating procedures","question":"Are operating procedures, and the documented procedures for system activities, treated as formal documents and changes authorized by management?","reason":"Responsibilities and procedures for the management and operation of all information processing facilities should be established. This includes the development of appropriate operating procedures. Segregation of duties should be implemented, where appropriate, to reduce the risk of negligent or deliberate system misuse.","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Windows operating system image is used to build laptops.  SonicWALL devices are managed consistently according to manual audit.  KACE is used for HW/SW inventory on most systems.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Documented Operating procedures","question":"Are information systems managed consistently, using the same procedures, tools, and utilities?","reason":"Responsibilities and procedures for the management and operation of all information processing facilities should be established. This includes the development of appropriate operating procedures. Segregation of duties should be implemented, where appropriate, to reduce the risk of negligent or deliberate system misuse.","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No formal Change/Configuration Management process.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Change Management","question":"Are changes to information processing facilities and systems controlled?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Change Management","question":"Are operational systems and application software subject to strict change management control?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Change Management","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for change management:&#10;a) identification and recording of significant changes;&#10;b) planning and testing of changes;&#10;c) assessment of the potential impacts, including security impacts, of such changes;&#10;d) formal approval procedure for proposed changes;&#10;e) communication of change details to all relevant persons;&#10;f) fallback procedures, including procedures and responsibilities for aborting and recovering from unsuccessful changes and unforeseen events?Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for change management:&#10;a) identification and recording of significant changes;&#10;b) planning and testing of changes;&#10;c) assessment of the potential impacts, including security impacts, of such changes;&#10;d) formal approval procedure for proposed changes;&#10;e) communication of change details to all relevant persons;&#10;f) fallback procedures, including procedures and responsibilities for aborting and recovering from unsuccessful changes and unforeseen events?Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for change management:&#10;a) identification and recording of significant changes;&#10;b) planning and testing of changes;&#10;c) assessment of the potential impacts, including security impacts, of such changes;&#10;d) formal approval procedure for proposed changes;&#10;e) communication of change details to all relevant persons;&#10;f) fallback procedures, including procedures and responsibilities for aborting and recovering from unsuccessful changes and unforeseen events?Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for change management:&#10;a) identification and recording of significant changes;&#10;b) planning and testing of changes;&#10;c) assessment of the potential impacts, including security impacts, of such changes;&#10;d) formal approval procedure for proposed changes;&#10;e) communication of change details to all relevant persons;&#10;f) fallback procedures, including procedures and responsibilities for aborting and recovering from unsuccessful changes and unforeseen events?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Change Management","question":"Are formal management responsibilities and procedures in place to ensure satisfactory control of all changes to equipment, software or procedures?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Change Management","question":"When changes are made, is an audit/change log containing all relevant information retained?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Change Management","question":"Are changes to operational systems only made when there is a valid business reason to do so, such as an increase in the risk to the system?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Segregation of duties","question":"Are duties and areas of responsibility segregated to reduce opportunities for unauthorized or unintentional modification or misuse of the organization‟s assets?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Segregation of duties","question":"Is due care taken so that no single person can access, modify or use assets without authorization or detection?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Segregation of duties","question":"Is the principle of segregation of duties applied as far as is possible and practicable?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Segregation of duties","question":"Whenever it is difficult to segregate, are other controls such as monitoring of activities, audit trails and management supervision considered?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Separation of development, test and operational facilities","question":"Are development, test, and operational facilities separated to reduce the risks of unauthorized access or changes to the operational system?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Separation of development, test and operational facilities","question":"Is the level of separation between operational, test, and development environments that is necessary to prevent operational problems identified and appropriate controls implemented?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Separation of development, test and operational facilities","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for separation of development, test, and operational facilities:&#10;a) rules for the transfer of software from development to operational status should be defined and documented;&#10;b) development and operational software should run on different systems or computer processors and in different domains or directories;&#10;c) compilers, editors, and other development tools or system utilities should not be accessible from operational systems when not required;&#10;d) the test system environment should emulate the operational system environment as closely as possible;&#10;e) users should use different user profiles for operational and test systems, and menus should display appropriate identification messages to reduce the risk of error;&#10;f) sensitive data should not be copied into the test system environment?Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for separation of development, test, and operational facilities:&#10;a) rules for the transfer of software from development to operational status should be defined and documented;&#10;b) development and operational software should run on different systems or computer processors and in different domains or directories;&#10;c) compilers, editors, and other development tools or system utilities should not be accessible from operational systems when not required;&#10;d) the test system environment should emulate the operational system environment as closely as possible;&#10;e) users should use different user profiles for operational and test systems, and menus should display appropriate identification messages to reduce the risk of error;&#10;f) sensitive data should not be copied into the test system environment?Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for separation of development, test, and operational facilities:&#10;a) rules for the transfer of software from development to operational status should be defined and documented;&#10;b) development and operational software should run on different systems or computer processors and in different domains or directories;&#10;c) compilers, editors, and other development tools or system utilities should not be accessible from operational systems when not required;&#10;d) the test system environment should emulate the operational system environment as closely as possible;&#10;e) users should use different user profiles for operational and test systems, and menus should display appropriate identification messages to reduce the risk of error;&#10;f) sensitive data should not be copied into the test system environment?","section":"Operational procedures and responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers -  We're just now starting to track SLAs with third parties.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Service Delivery","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Does the organization ensure that the security controls, service definitions and delivery levels included in the third party service delivery agreement are implemented, operated, and maintained by the third party?","reason":"The organization should check the implementation of agreements, monitor compliance with the agreements and manage changes to ensure that the services delivered meet all requirements agreed with the third party.","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Richard Jenkins - Included in our third party agreements.\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers - Yes.  PC Lender agreement does cover these topics.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Service Delivery","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does service delivery by a third party include the agreed security arrangements, service definitions, and aspects of service management?","reason":"The organization should check the implementation of agreements, monitor compliance with the agreements and manage changes to ensure that the services delivered meet all requirements agreed with the third party.","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Service Delivery","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"If the organization has outsourcing arrangements, does the organization plan the necessary transitions (of information, information processing facilities, and anything else that needs to be moved)?","reason":"The organization should check the implementation of agreements, monitor compliance with the agreements and manage changes to ensure that the services delivered meet all requirements agreed with the third party.","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":3,"text":"Automated on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Service Delivery","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"If the organization has outsourcing arrangements, does the organization ensure that security is maintained throughout the transition period?","reason":"The organization should check the implementation of agreements, monitor compliance with the agreements and manage changes to ensure that the services delivered meet all requirements agreed with the third party.","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers -","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Service Delivery","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization ensure that the third party maintains sufficient service capability together with workable plans designed to ensure that agreed service continuity levels are maintained following major service failures or disaster?","reason":"The organization should check the implementation of agreements, monitor compliance with the agreements and manage changes to ensure that the services delivered meet all requirements agreed with the third party.","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - Not for all.  PC Lender (example provided) doesn't provide this.  Other companies do provide this data and we do review it.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are the services, reports and records provided by the third party regularly monitored and reviewed?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - Yes.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are the third party services audited regularly?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers -  We do ask.  If yes, we do ask them to provide details.   Some contracts have language requiring third parties to notify us regarding security incidents.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the monitoring and review of third party services ensure that the information security terms and conditions of the agreements are being adhered to, and that information security incidents and problems are managed properly?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the monitoring and review of third party services involve a service management relationship and process between the organization and the third party to:&#10;a) monitor service performance levels to check adherence to the agreements;&#10;b) review service reports produced by the third party and arrange regular progress meetings as required by the agreements;&#10;c) provide information about information security incidents and review of this information by the third party and the organization as required by the agreements and any supporting guidelines and procedures;&#10;d) review third party audit trails and records of security events, operational problems, failures, tracing of faults and disruptions related to the service delivered;&#10;e) resolve and manage any identified problems?Does the monitoring and review of third party services involve a service management relationship and process between the organization and the third party to:&#10;a) monitor service performance levels to check adherence to the agreements;&#10;b) review service reports produced by the third party and arrange regular progress meetings as required by the agreements;&#10;c) provide information about information security incidents and review of this information by the third party and the organization as required by the agreements and any supporting guidelines and procedures;&#10;d) review third party audit trails and records of security events, operational problems, failures, tracing of faults and disruptions related to the service delivered;&#10;e) resolve and manage any identified problems?Does the monitoring and review of third party services involve a service management relationship and process between the organization and the third party to:&#10;a) monitor service performance levels to check adherence to the agreements;&#10;b) review service reports produced by the third party and arrange regular progress meetings as required by the agreements;&#10;c) provide information about information security incidents and review of this information by the third party and the organization as required by the agreements and any supporting guidelines and procedures;&#10;d) review third party audit trails and records of security events, operational problems, failures, tracing of faults and disruptions related to the service delivered;&#10;e) resolve and manage any identified problems?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers and Richard Jenkins","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Is the responsibility for managing the relationship with a third party assigned to a designated individual or service management team?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - Representatives are identified for our third party vendors.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization ensure that the third party assigns responsibilities for checking for compliance and enforcing the requirements of the agreements?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - All new contracts go through the Legal Department.  Contracts up for renewal (not many) also go back through legal.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","question":"Are sufficient technical skills and resources made available to monitor that requirements of the agreement, in particular the information security requirements, are being met?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - If our vendors don't provide the agreed upon services, we take appropriate action.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Are appropriate actions taken when deficiencies in the service delivery are observed?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization maintain sufficient overall control and visibility into all security aspects for sensitive or critical information or information processing facilities accessed, processed or managed by a third party?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring and review of third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Does the organization ensure they retain visibility into security activities such as change management, identification of vulnerabilities, and information security incident reporting/response through a clearly defined reporting process, format and structure?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Any material change to the contract should trigger a new risk assessment.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Managing changes to third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are changes to the provision of services, including maintaining and improving existing information security policies, procedures and controls, managed, taking account of the criticality of business systems and processes involved and re-assessment of risks?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Managing changes to third party services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for managing changes to third party services:&#10;a) changes made by the organization to implement:&#10;1) enhancements to the current services offered;&#10;2) development of any new applications and systems;&#10;3) modifications or updates of the organization‟s policies and procedures;&#10;4) new controls to resolve information security incidents and to improve security;&#10;b) changes in third party services to implement:&#10;1) changes and enhancement to networks;&#10;2) use of new technologies;&#10;3) adoption of new products or newer versions/releases;&#10;4) new development tools and environments;&#10;5) changes to physical location of service facilities;&#10;6) change of vendors?Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for managing changes to third party services:&#10;a) changes made by the organization to implement:&#10;1) enhancements to the current services offered;&#10;2) development of any new applications and systems;&#10;3) modifications or updates of the organization‟s policies and procedures;&#10;4) new controls to resolve information security incidents and to improve security;&#10;b) changes in third party services to implement:&#10;1) changes and enhancement to networks;&#10;2) use of new technologies;&#10;3) adoption of new products or newer versions/releases;&#10;4) new development tools and environments;&#10;5) changes to physical location of service facilities;&#10;6) change of vendors?","section":"Third party service delivery management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"Is the use of resources monitored, tuned, and projections made of future capacity requirements to ensure the required system performance?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"For each new and ongoing activity, are capacity requirements identified?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"Is system tuning and monitoring applied to ensure and, where necessary, improve the availability and efficiency of systems?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"Are detective controls put in place to indicate problems in due time?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"Do projections of future capacity requirements take account of new business and system requirements and current and projected trends in the organization's information processing capabilities?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No tools or capabilities exist to do capacity management.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"Do managers monitor the utilization of key system resources, paying particular attention to any resources with long procurement lead times or high costs?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"Do managers identify trends in usage, particularly in relation to business applications or management information system tools?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Capacity Management","question":"Do managers use this information to identify and avoid potential bottlenecks and dependence on key personnel that might present a threat to system security or services, and plan appropriate action?","reason":"Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use. Advance planning and preparation are required to ensure the availability of adequate capacity and resources to deliver the required system performance. &#10;&#10;Projections of future capacity requirements should be made, to reduce the risk of system overload. &#10;&#10;The operational requirements of new systems should be established, documented, and tested prior to their acceptance and use.","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"System acceptance","question":"Is acceptance criteria for new information systems, upgrades, and new versions established and suitable tests of the system(s) carried out during development and prior to acceptance?","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"System acceptance","question":"Do managers ensure that the requirements and criteria for acceptance of new systems are clearly defined, agreed, documented, and tested?","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"System acceptance","question":"Are new information systems, upgrades, and new versions only migrated into production after obtaining formal acceptance?","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"System acceptance","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate prior to formal acceptance being provided:&#10;a) performance and computer capacity requirements;&#10;b) error recovery and restart procedures, and contingency plans;&#10;c) preparation and testing of routine operating procedures to defined standards;&#10;d) agreed set of security controls in place;&#10;e) effective manual procedures;&#10;f) business continuity arrangements;&#10;g) evidence that installation of the new system will not adversely affect existing systems, particularly at peak processing times, such as month end;&#10;h) evidence that consideration has been given to the effect the new system has on the overall security of the organization;&#10;i) training in the operation or use of new systems;&#10;j) ease of use, as this affects user performance and avoids human error?Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate prior to formal acceptance being provided:&#10;a) performance and computer capacity requirements;&#10;b) error recovery and restart procedures, and contingency plans;&#10;c) preparation and testing of routine operating procedures to defined standards;&#10;d) agreed set of security controls in place;&#10;e) effective manual procedures;&#10;f) business continuity arrangements;&#10;g) evidence that installation of the new system will not adversely affect existing systems, particularly at peak processing times, such as month end;&#10;h) evidence that consideration has been given to the effect the new system has on the overall security of the organization;&#10;i) training in the operation or use of new systems;&#10;j) ease of use, as this affects user performance and avoids human error?","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"System acceptance","question":"For major new developments, are the operations function and users consulted at all stages in the development process to ensure the operational efficiency of the proposed system design?","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"System acceptance","question":"Are appropriate tests carried out to confirm that all acceptance criteria have been fully satisfied?","section":"System planning and acceptance","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Controls against malicious code","question":"Are detection, prevention, and recovery controls to protect against malicious code and appropriate user awareness procedures implemented?","reason":"Precautions are required to prevent and detect the introduction of malicious code and unauthorized mobile code. &#10;&#10;Software and information processing facilities are vulnerable to the introduction of malicious code, such as computer viruses, network worms, Trojan horses, and logic bombs. Users should be made aware of the dangers of malicious code. Managers should, where appropriate, introduce controls to prevent, detect, and remove malicious code and control mobile code.","section":"Planning against malicious and mobile code","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Controls against malicious code","question":"Is protection against malicious code based on malicious code detection and repair software, security awareness, and appropriate system access and change management controls?","reason":"Precautions are required to prevent and detect the introduction of malicious code and unauthorized mobile code. &#10;&#10;Software and information processing facilities are vulnerable to the introduction of malicious code, such as computer viruses, network worms, Trojan horses, and logic bombs. Users should be made aware of the dangers of malicious code. Managers should, where appropriate, introduce controls to prevent, detect, and remove malicious code and control mobile code.","section":"Planning against malicious and mobile code","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Controls against malicious code","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate prior to protect against malicious code:&#10;a) establishing a formal policy prohibiting the use of unauthorized software;&#10;b) establishing a formal policy to protect against risks associated with obtaining files and software either from or via external networks, or on any other medium, indicating what protective measures should be taken;&#10;c) conducting regular reviews of the software and data content of systems supporting critical business processes; the presence of any unapproved files or unauthorized amendments should be formally investigated;&#10;d) installation and regular update of malicious code detection and repair software to scan computers and media as a precautionary control, or on a routine basis; the checks carried out should include:&#10;1) checking any files on electronic or optical media, and files received over networks, for malicious code before use;&#10;2) checking electronic mail attachments and downloads for malicious code before use; this check should be carried out at different places, e.g. at electronic mail servers, desk top computers and when entering the network of the organization;&#10;3) checking web pages for malicious code;&#10;e) defining management procedures and responsibilities to deal with malicious code protection on systems, training in their use, reporting and recovering from malicious code attacks;&#10;f) preparing appropriate business continuity plans for recovering from malicious code attacks, including all necessary data and software back-up and recovery arrangements;&#10;g) implementing procedures to regularly collect information, such as subscribing to mailing lists and/or checking web sites giving information about new malicious code;&#10;h) implementing procedures to verify information relating to malicious code, and ensure that warning bulletins are accurate and informative; managers should ensure that qualified sources, e.g. reputable journals, reliable internet sites or suppliers producing software protecting against malicious code, are used to differentiate between hoaxes and real malicious code; all users should be made aware of the problem of hoaxes and what to do on receipt of them?","reason":"Precautions are required to prevent and detect the introduction of malicious code and unauthorized mobile code. &#10;&#10;Software and information processing facilities are vulnerable to the introduction of malicious code, such as computer viruses, network worms, Trojan horses, and logic bombs. Users should be made aware of the dangers of malicious code. Managers should, where appropriate, introduce controls to prevent, detect, and remove malicious code and control mobile code.","section":"Planning against malicious and mobile code","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Controls against malicious code","question":"Is due care taken to protect against the introduction of malicious code during maintenance and emergency procedures, which may bypass normal malicious code protection controls?","reason":"Precautions are required to prevent and detect the introduction of malicious code and unauthorized mobile code. &#10;&#10;Software and information processing facilities are vulnerable to the introduction of malicious code, such as computer viruses, network worms, Trojan horses, and logic bombs. Users should be made aware of the dangers of malicious code. Managers should, where appropriate, introduce controls to prevent, detect, and remove malicious code and control mobile code.","section":"Planning against malicious and mobile code","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Controls against mobile code","question":"Where the use of mobile code is authorized, does the configuration ensure that the authorized mobile code operates according to a clearly defined security policy, and unauthorized&#10;mobile code is prevented from executing?","reason":"Precautions are required to prevent and detect the introduction of malicious code and unauthorized mobile code. &#10;&#10;Software and information processing facilities are vulnerable to the introduction of malicious code, such as computer viruses, network worms, Trojan horses, and logic bombs. Users should be made aware of the dangers of malicious code. Managers should, where appropriate, introduce controls to prevent, detect, and remove malicious code and control mobile code.","section":"Planning against malicious and mobile code","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Controls against mobile code","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate prior to protect against mobile code performing unauthorized actions:&#10;a) executing mobile code in a logically isolated environment;&#10;b) blocking any use of mobile code;&#10;c) blocking receipt of mobile code;&#10;d) activating technical measures as available on a specific system to ensure mobile code is managed;&#10;e) controlling the resources available to mobile code access;&#10;f) cryptographic controls to uniquely authenticate mobile code?","reason":"Precautions are required to prevent and detect the introduction of malicious code and unauthorized mobile code. &#10;&#10;Software and information processing facilities are vulnerable to the introduction of malicious code, such as computer viruses, network worms, Trojan horses, and logic bombs. Users should be made aware of the dangers of malicious code. Managers should, where appropriate, introduce controls to prevent, detect, and remove malicious code and control mobile code.","section":"Planning against malicious and mobile code","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information back-up","question":"Are back-up copies of information and software taken and tested regularly in accordance with the agreed backup policy?","reason":"Routine procedures should be established to implement the agreed back-up policy and strategy for taking back-up copies of data and rehearsing their timely restoration.","section":"Back-up","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information back-up","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for information back-up:&#10;a) the necessary level of back-up information should be defined;&#10;b) accurate and complete records of the back-up copies and documented restoration procedures should be produced;&#10;c) the extent (e.g. full or differential backup) and frequency of backups should reflect the business requirements of the organization, the security requirements of the information involved, and the criticality of the information to the continued operation of the organization;&#10;d) the back-ups should be stored in a remote location, at a sufficient distance to escape any damage from a disaster at the main site;&#10;e) back-up information should be given an appropriate level of physical and environmental protection consistent with the standards applied at the main site; the controls applied to media at the main site should be extended to cover the back-up site;&#10;f) back-up media should be regularly tested to ensure that they can be relied upon for emergency use when necessary;&#10;g) restoration procedures should be regularly checked and tested to ensure that they are effective and that they can be completed within the time allotted in the operational procedures for recovery;&#10;h) in situations where confidentiality is of importance, back-ups should be protected by means of encryption?","reason":"Routine procedures should be established to implement the agreed back-up policy and strategy for taking back-up copies of data and rehearsing their timely restoration.","section":"Back-up","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information back-up","question":"Are back-up arrangements for individual systems regularly tested to ensure that they meet the requirements of business continuity plans?","reason":"Routine procedures should be established to implement the agreed back-up policy and strategy for taking back-up copies of data and rehearsing their timely restoration.","section":"Back-up","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information back-up","question":"For critical systems, do the backup arrangements cover all systems information, applications, and data necessary to recover the complete system in the event of a disaster?","reason":"Routine procedures should be established to implement the agreed back-up policy and strategy for taking back-up copies of data and rehearsing their timely restoration.","section":"Back-up","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information back-up","question":"Is the retention period for essential business information, and also any requirement for archive copies to be permanently retained determined?","reason":"Routine procedures should be established to implement the agreed back-up policy and strategy for taking back-up copies of data and rehearsing their timely restoration.","section":"Back-up","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information back-up","question":"Are automated backup arrangements sufficiently tested prior to implementation and at regular intervals?","reason":"Routine procedures should be established to implement the agreed back-up policy and strategy for taking back-up copies of data and rehearsing their timely restoration.","section":"Back-up","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Monitoring of networks is non-existent.    Separation of business units is not in place.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Network controls","question":"Are networks adequately managed and controlled, in order to be protected from threats, and to maintain security for the systems and applications using the network, including information in transit?","reason":"The secure management of networks, which may span organizational boundaries, requires careful consideration to dataflow, legal implications, monitoring, and protection. &#10;&#10;Additional controls may also be required to protect sensitive information passing over public networks.","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Auditors were able to access the production network from the guest wireless network through an unsecured wireless device.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Network controls","question":"Have network managers implemented controls to ensure the security of information in networks, and the protection of connected services from unauthorized access?","reason":"The secure management of networks, which may span organizational boundaries, requires careful consideration to dataflow, legal implications, monitoring, and protection. &#10;&#10;Additional controls may also be required to protect sensitive information passing over public networks.","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Network controls","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate to provide network security:&#10;a) operational responsibility for networks should be separated from computer operations where appropriate;&#10;b) responsibilities and procedures for the management of remote equipment, including equipment in user areas, should be established;&#10;c) special controls should be established to safeguard the confidentiality and integrity of data passing over public networks or over wireless networks, and to protect the connected systems and applications; special controls may also be required to maintain the availability of the network services and computers connected;&#10;d) appropriate logging and monitoring should be applied to enable recording of security relevant actions;&#10;e) management activities should be closely co-ordinated both to optimize the service to the organization and to ensure that controls are consistently applied across the information processing infrastructure?","reason":"The secure management of networks, which may span organizational boundaries, requires careful consideration to dataflow, legal implications, monitoring, and protection. &#10;&#10;Additional controls may also be required to protect sensitive information passing over public networks.","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Security of network services","question":"Are security features, service levels, and management requirements of all network services identified and included in any network services agreement, whether these services are provided inhouse or outsourced?","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Security of network services","question":"Has the ability of the network service provider to manage agreed services in a secure way been determined and regularly monitored?","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Security of network services","question":"Has a right to audit the network service provider been agreed?","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Security of network services","question":"Has the security arrangements necessary for particular services, such as security features, service levels, and management requirements, been identified?","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Security of network services","question":"Does the organization ensure that network service providers implement these measures?","section":"Network security management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Default laptop image blocks USB writes.","control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Management of removable media","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Are there procedures in place for the management of removable media?","reason":"Media should be controlled and physically protected. Appropriate operating procedures should be established to protect documents, computer media (e.g. tapes, disks), input/output data and system documentation from unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, and destruction.","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":25},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Management of removable media","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for management of removable media:&#10;a) if no longer required, the contents of any re-usable media that are to be removed from the organization should be made unrecoverable;&#10;a) processing and handling of information;&#10;b) where necessary and practical, authorization should be required for media removed from the organization and a record of such removals should be kept in order to maintain an audit trail;&#10;c) all media should be stored in a safe, secure environment, in accordance with manufacturers‟ specifications;&#10;d) information stored on media that needs to be available longer than the media lifetime (in accordance with manufacturers‟ specifications) should be also stored elsewhere to avoid information loss due to media deterioration;&#10;e) registration of removable media should be considered to limit the opportunity for data loss;&#10;f) removable media drives should only be enabled if there is a business reason for doing so?","reason":"Media should be controlled and physically protected. Appropriate operating procedures should be established to protect documents, computer media (e.g. tapes, disks), input/output data and system documentation from unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, and destruction.","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"There is an informal policy for sanitization and destruction of media.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Disposal of Media","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Is media disposed of securely and safely when no longer required, using formal procedures?","reason":"Media should be controlled and physically protected. Appropriate operating procedures should be established to protect documents, computer media (e.g. tapes, disks), input/output data and system documentation from unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, and destruction.","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Disposal of Media","question":"Do formal procedures for the secure disposal of media minimize the risk of sensitive information leakage to unauthorized persons?","reason":"Media should be controlled and physically protected. Appropriate operating procedures should be established to protect documents, computer media (e.g. tapes, disks), input/output data and system documentation from unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, and destruction.","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Disposal of Media","question":"Are the procedures for secure disposal of media containing sensitive information commensurate with the sensitivity of that information?","reason":"Media should be controlled and physically protected. Appropriate operating procedures should be established to protect documents, computer media (e.g. tapes, disks), input/output data and system documentation from unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, and destruction.","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Disposal of Media","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for the disposal of media:&#10;a) media containing sensitive information should be stored and disposed of securely and safely, e.g. by incineration or shredding, or erased of data for use by another application within the organization;&#10;b) procedures should be in place to identify the items that might require secure disposal;&#10;c) it may be easier to arrange for all media items to be collected and disposed of securely, rather than attempting to separate out the sensitive items;&#10;d) many organizations offer collection and disposal services for papers, equipment and media; care should be taken in selecting a suitable contractor with adequate controls and experience;&#10;e) disposal of sensitive items should be logged where possible in order to maintain an audit trail?","reason":"Media should be controlled and physically protected. Appropriate operating procedures should be established to protect documents, computer media (e.g. tapes, disks), input/output data and system documentation from unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, and destruction.","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Disposal of Media","question":"When accumulating media for disposal, is consideration given to the aggregation effect, which may cause a large quantity of non-sensitive information to become sensitive?","reason":"Media should be controlled and physically protected. Appropriate operating procedures should be established to protect documents, computer media (e.g. tapes, disks), input/output data and system documentation from unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, and destruction.","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information handling procedures","question":"Are procedures for the handling and storage of information established to protect this information from unauthorized disclosure or misuse?","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information handling procedures","question":"Are procedures drawn up for handling, processing, storing, and communicating information consistent with its classification?","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information handling procedures","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for information handling procedures:&#10;a) handling and labeling of all media to its indicated classification level;&#10;b) access restrictions to prevent access from unauthorized personnel;&#10;c) maintenance of a formal record of the authorized recipients of data;&#10;d) ensuring that input data is complete, that processing is properly completed and that output validation is applied;&#10;e) protection of spooled data awaiting output to a level consistent with its sensitivity;&#10;f) storage of media in accordance with manufacturers‟ specifications;&#10;g) keeping the distribution of data to a minimum;&#10;h) clear marking of all copies of media for the attention of the authorized recipient;&#10;i) review of distribution lists and lists of authorized recipients at regular intervals?","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Security of system documentation","question":"Is system documentation protected against unauthorized access?","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Security of system documentation","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for security of system documentation:&#10;a) system documentation should be stored securely;&#10;b) the access list for system documentation should be kept to a minimum and authorized by the application owner;&#10;c) system documentation held on a public network, or supplied via a public network, should be appropriately protected?","section":"Media handling","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information exchange policies and procedures","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are formal exchange policies, procedures, and controls in place to protect the exchange of information through the use of all types of communication facilities?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information exchange policies and procedures","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate when using electronic communication facilities for information exchange:&#10;a) procedures designed to protect exchanged information from interception, copying, modification, mis-routing, and destruction;&#10;b) procedures for the detection of and protection against malicious code that may be transmitted through the use of electronic communications;&#10;c) procedures for protecting communicated sensitive electronic information that is in the form of an attachment;&#10;d) policy or guidelines outlining acceptable use of electronic communication facilities;&#10;e) procedures for the use of wireless communications, taking into account the particular risks involved;&#10;f) employee, contractor and any other user's responsibilities not to compromise the organization, e.g. through defamation, harassment, impersonation, forwarding of chain letters, unauthorized purchasing, etc.;&#10;g) use of cryptographic techniques e.g. to protect the confidentiality, integrity and authenticity of information;&#10;h) retention and disposal guidelines for all business correspondence, including messages, in accordance with relevant national and local legislation and regulations;&#10;i) not leaving sensitive or critical information on printing facilities, e.g. copiers, printers, and facsimile machines, as these may be accessed by unauthorized personnel;&#10;j) controls and restrictions associated with the forwarding of communication facilities, e.g. automatic forwarding of electronic mail to external mail addresses;&#10;k) reminding personnel that they should take appropriate precautions, e.g. not to reveal sensitive information to avoid being overheard or intercepted when making a phone call by:&#10; 1) people in their immediate vicinity particularly when using mobile phones;&#10; 2) wiretapping, and other forms of eavesdropping through physical access to the phone handset or the phone line, or using scanning receivers;&#10; 3) people at the recipient‟s end;&#10;l) not leaving messages containing sensitive information on answering machines since these may be replayed by unauthorized persons, stored on communal systems or stored incorrectly as a result of misdialing;&#10;m) reminding personnel about the problems of using facsimile machines, namely:&#10; 1) unauthorized access to built-in message stores to retrieve messages;&#10; 2) deliberate or accidental programming of machines to send messages to specific numbers;&#10; 3) sending documents and messages to the wrong number either by misdialing or using the wrong stored number;&#10;n) reminding personnel not to register demographic data, such as the e-mail address or other personal information, in any software to avoid collection for unauthorized use;&#10;o) reminding personnel that modern facsimile machines and photocopiers have page caches and store pages in case of a paper or transmission fault, which will be printed once the fault is cleared?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information exchange policies and procedures","question":"Are personnel reminded that they should not have confidential conversations in public places or open offices and meeting places with non-sound proofed-walls?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information exchange policies and procedures","question":"Do information exchange facilities comply with any relevant legal requirements?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Information exchange policies and procedures","question":"Are the business, legal, and security implications associated with electronic data interchange, electronic commerce, and electronic communications and the requirements for controls considered?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers -","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Exchange Agreements","question":"Are agreements established for the exchange of information and software between the organization and external parties?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers -","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Exchange Agreements","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for exchange agreements:&#10;a) management responsibilities for controlling and notifying transmission, dispatch, and receipt;&#10;b) procedures for notifying sender of transmission, dispatch, and receipt;&#10;c) procedures to ensure traceability and non-repudiation;&#10;d) minimum technical standards for packaging and transmission;&#10;e) escrow agreements;&#10;f) courier identification standards;&#10;g) responsibilities and liabilities in the event of information security incidents, such as loss of data;&#10;h) use of an agreed labeling system for sensitive or critical information, ensuring that the meaning of the labels is immediately understood and that the information is appropriately protected;&#10;i) ownership and responsibilities for data protection, copyright, software license compliance and similar considerations;&#10;j) technical standards for recording and reading information and software;&#10;k) any special controls that may be required to protect sensitive items, such as cryptographic keys?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - No","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Exchange Agreements","question":"Are policies, procedures, and standards established and maintained to protect information and physical media in transit?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - No","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Exchange Agreements","question":"Are policies, procedures, and standards established and maintained to protect information and physical media in referenced in such exchange agreements?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Verified by review","customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - PC Lender agreement has this language.  Standard of Care for Confidential Information section of the agreement.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Exchange Agreements","question":"Does the security content of any agreement reflect the sensitivity of the business information involved?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Couldn't find any reference to specific mechanisms (use of encryption for file transfer/authentication, etc.) in any of the agreements.","customer_response":"Brett Rodgers - Don't think so.  Will look into this.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Exchange Agreements","question":"For sensitive information, are the specific mechanisms used for the exchange of such information consistent for all organizations and types of agreements?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Physical media in transit","question":"Is media containing information protected against unauthorized access, misuse, or corruption during transportation beyond an organization’s physical boundaries?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Physical media in transit","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate to protect information media being transported between sites:&#10;a) reliable transport or couriers should be used;&#10;b) a list of authorized couriers should be agreed with management;&#10;c) procedures to check the identification of couriers should be developed;&#10;d) packaging should be sufficient to protect the contents from any physical damage likely to arise during transit and in accordance with any manufacturers‟ specifications (e.g. for software), for example protecting against any environmental factors that may reduce the media‟s restoration effectiveness such as exposure to heat, moisture or electromagnetic fields;&#10;e) controls should be adopted, where necessary, to protect sensitive information from unauthorized disclosure or modification; examples include:&#10;1) use of locked containers;&#10;2) delivery by hand;&#10;3) tamper-evident packaging (which reveals any attempt to gain access);","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"ZixCorp email encryption utility is available for use.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Electronic messaging","question":"Is information involved in electronic messaging appropriately protected?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology 10.8;  (§ 103(a)(2)(A)(iii)(II)(bb), The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Electronic messaging","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for electronic messaging:&#10;a) protecting messages from unauthorized access, modification or denial of service;&#10;b) ensuring correct addressing and transportation of the message;&#10;c) general reliability and availability of the service;&#10;d) legal considerations, for example requirements for electronic signatures;&#10;e) obtaining approval prior to using external public services such as instant messaging or file sharing;&#10;f) stronger levels of authentication controlling access from publicly accessible networks?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology 10.8;  (§ 103(a)(2)(A)(iii)(II)(bb), The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Business Information systems","question":"Have policies and procedures been developed and implemented to protect information associated with the interconnection of business information systems?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Business Information systems","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate to the security and business implications of interconnecting such facilities:&#10;a) known vulnerabilities in the administrative and accounting systems where information is shared between different parts of the organization;&#10;b) vulnerabilities of information in business communication systems, e.g. recording phone calls or conference calls, confidentiality of calls, storage of facsimiles, opening mail, distribution of mail;&#10;c) policy and appropriate controls to manage information sharing;&#10;d) excluding categories of sensitive business information and classified documents if the system does not provide an appropriate level of protection;&#10;e) restricting access to diary information relating to selected individuals, e.g. personnel working on sensitive projects;&#10;f) categories of personnel, contractors or business partners allowed to use the system and the locations from which it may be accessed;&#10;g) restricting selected facilities to specific categories of user;&#10;h) identifying the status of users, e.g. employees of the organization or contractors in directories for the benefit of other users;&#10;i) retention and back-up of information held on the system;&#10;j) fallback requirements and arrangement?","section":"Exchange of information","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Electronic commerce","question":"Is information involved in electronic commerce passing over public networks protected from fraudulent activity, contract dispute, and unauthorized disclosure and modification?","reason":"The security implications associated with using electronic commerce services, including on-line transactions, and the requirements for controls, should be considered. The integrity and availability of information electronically published through publicly available systems should also be considered.","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Electronic commerce","question":"Is security consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate when using electronic commerce:&#10;a) the level of confidence each party requires in each other‟s claimed identity, e.g. through authentication;&#10;b) authorization processes associated with who may set prices, issue or sign key trading documents;&#10;c) ensuring that trading partners are fully informed of their authorizations;&#10;d) determining and meeting requirements for confidentiality, integrity, proof of dispatch and receipt of key documents, and the non-repudiation of contracts, e.g. associated with tendering and contract processes;&#10;e) the level of trust required in the integrity of advertised price lists;&#10;f) the confidentiality of any sensitive data or information;&#10;g) the confidentiality and integrity of any order transactions, payment information, delivery address details, and confirmation of receipts;&#10;h) the degree of verification appropriate to check payment information supplied by a customer;&#10;i) selecting the most appropriate settlement form of payment to guard against fraud;&#10;j) the level of protection required to maintain the confidentiality and integrity of order information;&#10;k) avoidance of loss or duplication of transaction information;&#10;l) liability associated with any fraudulent transactions;&#10;m) insurance requirements?","reason":"The security implications associated with using electronic commerce services, including on-line transactions, and the requirements for controls, should be considered. The integrity and availability of information electronically published through publicly available systems should also be considered.","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Electronic commerce","question":"Are electronic commerce arrangements between trading partners supported by a documented agreement which commits both parties to the agreed terms of trading, including details of authorization?","reason":"The security implications associated with using electronic commerce services, including on-line transactions, and the requirements for controls, should be considered. The integrity and availability of information electronically published through publicly available systems should also be considered.","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Electronic commerce","question":"If public trading systems are supported do they publicize their terms of business to customers?","reason":"The security implications associated with using electronic commerce services, including on-line transactions, and the requirements for controls, should be considered. The integrity and availability of information electronically published through publicly available systems should also be considered.","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Electronic commerce","question":"Is consideration given to the resilience to attack of the host(s) used for electronic commerce, and the security implications of any network interconnection required for the implementation of electronic commerce services?","reason":"The security implications associated with using electronic commerce services, including on-line transactions, and the requirements for controls, should be considered. The integrity and availability of information electronically published through publicly available systems should also be considered.","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"On-Line Transactions","question":"Is information involved in on-line transactions protected to prevent incomplete transmission, mis-routing, unauthorized message alteration, unauthorized disclosure, unauthorized message duplication or replay?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology 10.8;  (§ 103(a)(2)(A)(iii)(II)(bb), The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"On-Line Transactions","question":"Is security consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for on-line transactions:&#10;a) the use of electronic signatures by each of the parties involved in the transaction;&#10;b) all aspects of the transaction, i.e. ensuring that:&#10;1) user credentials of all parties are valid and verified;&#10;2) the transaction remains confidential; and&#10;3) privacy associated with all parties involved is retained;&#10;c) communications path between all involved parties is encrypted;&#10;d) protocols used to communicate between all involved parties is secured;&#10;e) ensuring that the storage of the transaction details are located outside of any public accessible environment, e.g. on a storage platform existing on the organizational intranet, and not retained and exposed on a storage medium directly accessible from the internet;&#10;f) where a trusted authority is used (e.g. for the purposes of issuing and maintaining digital signatures and/or digital certificates) security is integrated and embedded throughout the entire end-to-end certificate/signature management process?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology 10.8;  (§ 103(a)(2)(A)(iii)(II)(bb), The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Publicly available information","question":"Is the integrity of information being made available on a publicly available system protected to prevent unauthorized modification?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology 10.8;  (§ 103(a)(2)(A)(iii)(II)(bb), The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Publicly available information","question":"Is software, data, and other information requiring a high level of integrity, being made available on a publicly available system, protected by appropriate mechanisms, e.g. digital signatures?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Publicly available information","question":"Is the publicly accessible system tested against weaknesses and failures prior to information being made available?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Publicly available information","question":"Is there a formal approval process before information is made publicly available?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Publicly available information","question":"Is all input provided from the outside to the system verified and approved?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Publicly available information","question":"Are electronic publishing systems, especially those that permit feedback and direct entering of information, carefully controlled so that:&#10;a) information is obtained in compliance with any data protection legislation;&#10;b) information input to, and processed by, the publishing system will be processed completely and accurately in a timely manner;&#10;c) sensitive information will be protected during collection, processing, and storage;&#10;d) access to the publishing system does not allow unintended access to networks to which the system is connected?","section":"Electronic commerce services","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Audit Logging","question":"Are audit logs recording user activities, exceptions, and information security events produced and kept for an agreed period to assist in future investigations and access control monitoring?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Audit Logging","question":"Do audit logs include, when relevant:&#10;a) user IDs;&#10;b) dates, times, and details of key events, e.g. log-on and log-off;&#10;c) terminal identity or location if possible;&#10;d) records of successful and rejected system access attempts;&#10;e) records of successful and rejected data and other resource access attempts;&#10;f) changes to system configuration;&#10;g) use of privileges;&#10;h) use of system utilities and applications;&#10;i) files accessed and the kind of access;&#10;j) network addresses and protocols;&#10;k) alarms raised by the access control system;&#10;l) activation and de-activation of protection systems, such as anti-virus systems and intrusion detection systems?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Audit Logging","question":"Are appropriate privacy protection measures taken for audit logs which may contain intrusive and confidential personal data?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Audit Logging","question":"Do system administrators have permission to erase or de-activate logs of their own activities? (NOTE: YES is a bad answer)","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring System Use","question":"Are procedures for monitoring use of information processing facilities established and the results of the monitoring activities reviewed regularly?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring System Use","question":"Is the level of monitoring required for individual facilities determined by a risk assessment?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring System Use","question":"Does the organization comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring activities?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring System Use","question":"Is security consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for monitoring system use:&#10;a) authorized access, including detail such as:&#10;1) the user ID;&#10;2) the date and time of key events;&#10;3) the types of events;&#10;4) the files accessed;&#10;5) the program/utilities used;&#10;b) all privileged operations, such as:&#10;1) use of privileged accounts, e.g. supervisor, root, administrator;&#10;2) system start-up and stop;&#10;3) I/O device attachment/detachment;&#10;c) unauthorized access attempts, such as:&#10;1) failed or rejected user actions;&#10;2) failed or rejected actions involving data and other resources;&#10;3) access policy violations and notifications for network gateways and firewalls;&#10;4) alerts from proprietary intrusion detection systems;&#10;d) system alerts or failures such as:&#10;1) console alerts or messages;&#10;2) system log exceptions;&#10;3) network management alarms;&#10;4) alarms raised by the access control system;&#10;e) changes to, or attempts to change, system security settings and controls?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring System Use","question":"Does the frequency the results of monitoring activities are reviewed depend on the risks involved?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Monitoring System Use","question":"Do the risk factors that are considered include the:&#10;a) criticality of the application processes;&#10;b) value, sensitivity, and criticality of the information involved;&#10;c) past experience of system infiltration and misuse, and the frequency of vulnerabilities being exploited;&#10;d) extent of system interconnection (particularly public networks);&#10;e) logging facility being de-activated?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Protection of log information","question":"Are logging facilities and log information protected against tampering and unauthorized access?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Protection of log information","question":"Do controls aim to protect against unauthorized changes and operational problems with the logging facility include:&#10;a) alterations to the message types that are recorded;&#10;b) log files being edited or deleted;&#10;c) storage capacity of the log file media being exceeded, resulting in either the failure to record events or over-writing of past recorded events?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Protection of log information","question":"Because of the large volume of information, much of which is extraneous to security monitoring, is consideration given to identify significant events for security monitoring purposes, the copying of appropriate message types automatically to a second log, and/or the use of suitable system utilities or audit tools to perform file interrogation and rationalization?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Administrator and operator logs","question":"Are system administrator and system operator activities logged?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Administrator and operator logs","question":"Is security consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for administrator and operator logs:&#10;a) the time at which an event (success or failure) occurred;&#10;b) information about the event (e.g. files handled) or failure (e.g. error occurred and corrective action taken);&#10;c) which account and which administrator or operator was involved;&#10;d) which processes were involved.","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Administrator and operator logs","question":"Are system administrator and operator logs reviewed on a regular basis?","reason":"Systems should be monitored and information security events should be recorded. Operator logs and fault logging should be used to ensure information system problems are identified. An organization should comply with all relevant legal requirements applicable to its monitoring and logging activities. System monitoring should be used to check the effectiveness of controls adopted and to verify conformity to an access policy model.","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Fault logging","question":"Are faults logged, analyzed, and appropriate action taken?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No formal helpdesk ticket system is in place to report or track system faults.","domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Fault logging","question":"Are faults reported by users or by system programs related to problems with information processing or communications systems logged?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Fault logging","question":"Are there clear rules for handling reported faults including:&#10;a) review of fault logs to ensure that faults have been satisfactorily resolved;&#10;b) review of corrective measures to ensure that controls have not been compromised, and that the action taken is fully authorized?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Fault logging","question":"Does the organization ensure that error logging is enabled, if this system function is available?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Fault logging","question":"Is logging of errors and faults enabled by competent personnel, and the level of logging required for individual systems determined by a risk assessment, taking performance degradation into account?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Clock Synchronization","question":"Are the clocks of all relevant information processing systems within an organization or security domain synchronized with an agreed accurate time source?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Clock Synchronization","question":"Where a computer or communications device has the capability to operate a real-time clock, is this clock set to an agreed standard, e.g. Coordinated Universal Time (UTC) or local standard time?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Clock Synchronization","question":"As some clocks are known to drift with time, is there a procedure that checks for and corrects any significant variation?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Clock Synchronization","question":"The correct interpretation of the date/time format is important to ensure that the timestamp reflects the real date/time. Are local specifics (e.g. daylight savings) taken into account?","section":"Monitoring","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Network Device Logs","question":"Whether network boundary devices, including firewalls, network-based IPS, and inbound and outbound proxies, are configured to verbosely log all traffic (both allowed and blocked) arriving at the device.","section":"Monitoring","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Communication and Operations Management","objective":"Centralized Log File Consolidation","question":"Whether a SIEM (Security Incident and Event Management) or log analytic tools for log aggregation and consolidation from multiple machines and for log correlation and analysis has been deployed.  Ensure that the log collection system does not lose events during peak activity, and that the system detects and alerts if event loss occurs.","section":"Monitoring","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"There is no policy that addresses user account management, access enforcement, separation of duties, and remote access.  An Access Control program helps the organization implement security best practices with regard to logical security, account management, and remote access.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Access control policy","question":"Has an access control policy been established, documented, and reviewed based on business and security requirements for access?","reason":"Access to information, information processing facilities, and business processes should be controlled on the basis of business and security requirements. Access control rules should take account of policies for information dissemination and authorization.","section":"Business requirement for access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Access control policy","question":"Are access control rules and rights for each user or group of users clearly stated in an access control policy?","reason":"Access to information, information processing facilities, and business processes should be controlled on the basis of business and security requirements. Access control rules should take account of policies for information dissemination and authorization.","section":"Business requirement for access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Access control policy","question":"Are both logical and physical access controls considered together?","reason":"Access to information, information processing facilities, and business processes should be controlled on the basis of business and security requirements. Access control rules should take account of policies for information dissemination and authorization.","section":"Business requirement for access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Access control policy","question":"Are users and service providers given a clear statement of the business requirements to be met by access controls?","reason":"Access to information, information processing facilities, and business processes should be controlled on the basis of business and security requirements. Access control rules should take account of policies for information dissemination and authorization.","section":"Business requirement for access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Access control policy","question":"Does the access control policy take account of the following:&#10;a) security requirements of individual business applications;&#10;b) identification of all information related to the business applications and the risks the information is facing;&#10;c) policies for information dissemination and authorization, e.g. the need to know principle and security levels and classification of information;&#10;d) consistency between the access control and information classification policies of different systems and networks;&#10;e) relevant legislation and any contractual obligations regarding protection of access to data or services);&#10;f) standard user access profiles for common job roles in the organization;&#10;g) management of access rights in a distributed and networked environment which recognizes all types of connections available;&#10;h) segregation of access control roles, e.g. access request, access authorization, access administration;&#10;i) requirements for formal authorization of access requests;&#10;j) requirements for periodic review of access controls;&#10;k) removal of access rights?","reason":"Access to information, information processing facilities, and business processes should be controlled on the basis of business and security requirements. Access control rules should take account of policies for information dissemination and authorization.","section":"Business requirement for access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Access control policy","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for access control rules:&#10;a) differentiating between rules that must always be enforced and guidelines that are optional or conditional;&#10;b) establishing rules based on the premise “Everything is generally forbidden unless expressly permitted” rather than the weaker rule “Everything is generally permitted unless&#10;expressly forbidden”;&#10;c) changes in information labels that are initiated automatically by information processing facilities and those initiated at the discretion of a user;&#10;d) changes in user permissions that are initiated automatically by the information system and those initiated by an administrator;&#10;e) rules, which require specific approval before enactment, and those which do not?","reason":"Access to information, information processing facilities, and business processes should be controlled on the basis of business and security requirements. Access control rules should take account of policies for information dissemination and authorization.","section":"Business requirement for access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Access control policy","question":"Are access control rules supported by formal procedures and clearly defined responsibilities?","reason":"Access to information, information processing facilities, and business processes should be controlled on the basis of business and security requirements. Access control rules should take account of policies for information dissemination and authorization.","section":"Business requirement for access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"User registration / removal process is managed through emails and not a formal help-desk system.  There is a written policy that discusses user removal briefly.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User registration","policy_defined":{"id":3,"text":"Written Policy","value":0.75},"question":"Is there a formal user registration and de-registration procedure in place for granting and revoking access to all information systems and services?","reason":"Formal procedures should be in place to control the allocation of access rights to information systems and services. The procedures should cover all stages in the life-cycle of user access, from the initial registration of new users to the final de-registration of users who no longer require access to information systems and services. Special attention should be given, where appropriate, to the need to control the allocation of privileged access rights, which allow users to override system controls.","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":75},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User registration","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for the access control procedure for user registration and de-registration:&#10;a) using unique user IDs to enable users to be linked to and held responsible for their actions; the use of group IDs should only be permitted where they are necessary for business or operational reasons, and should be approved and documented;&#10;b) checking that the user has authorization from the system owner for the use of the information system or service; separate approval for access rights from management may also be appropriate;&#10;c) checking that the level of access granted is appropriate to the business purpose and is consistent with organizational security policy, e.g. it does not compromise segregation of duties;&#10;d) giving users a written statement of their access rights;&#10;e) requiring users to sign statements indicating that they understand the conditions of access;&#10;f) ensuring service providers do not provide access until authorization procedures have been completed;&#10;g) maintaining a formal record of all persons registered to use the service;&#10;h) immediately removing or blocking access rights of users who have changed roles or jobs or left the organization;&#10;i) periodically checking for, and removing or blocking, redundant user IDs and accounts;&#10;j) ensuring that redundant user IDs are not issued to other users?","reason":"Formal procedures should be in place to control the allocation of access rights to information systems and services. The procedures should cover all stages in the life-cycle of user access, from the initial registration of new users to the final de-registration of users who no longer require access to information systems and services. Special attention should be given, where appropriate, to the need to control the allocation of privileged access rights, which allow users to override system controls.","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User registration","question":"Is consideration given to establish user access roles based on business requirements that summarize a number of access rights into typical user access profiles?","reason":"Formal procedures should be in place to control the allocation of access rights to information systems and services. The procedures should cover all stages in the life-cycle of user access, from the initial registration of new users to the final de-registration of users who no longer require access to information systems and services. Special attention should be given, where appropriate, to the need to control the allocation of privileged access rights, which allow users to override system controls.","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Covered in Employee Handbook.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User registration","question":"Is consideration given to including clauses in personnel contracts and service contracts that specify sanctions if unauthorized access is attempted by personnel or service?","reason":"Formal procedures should be in place to control the allocation of access rights to information systems and services. The procedures should cover all stages in the life-cycle of user access, from the initial registration of new users to the final de-registration of users who no longer require access to information systems and services. Special attention should be given, where appropriate, to the need to control the allocation of privileged access rights, which allow users to override system controls.","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Implemented on network infrastructure hardware, but not within PC Lender, and Office 365.    Observed use of group and account sharing within PC Lender and Office 365.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Privilege management","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Is the allocation and use of privileges restricted and controlled?","reason":"Formal procedures should be in place to control the allocation of access rights to information systems and services. The procedures should cover all stages in the life-cycle of user access, from the initial registration of new users to the final de-registration of users who no longer require access to information systems and services. Special attention should be given, where appropriate, to the need to control the allocation of privileged access rights, which allow users to override system controls.","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":50},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No formal authorization process observed","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Privilege management","question":"For multi-user systems that require protection against unauthorized access is the allocation of privileges controlled through a formal authorization process?","reason":"Formal procedures should be in place to control the allocation of access rights to information systems and services. The procedures should cover all stages in the life-cycle of user access, from the initial registration of new users to the final de-registration of users who no longer require access to information systems and services. Special attention should be given, where appropriate, to the need to control the allocation of privileged access rights, which allow users to override system controls.","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Privilege management","question":"Is consideration given to the following steps and implemented where appropriate for privilege management:&#10;a) the access privileges associated with each system product, e.g. operating system, database management system and each application, and the users to which they need to be allocated should be identified;&#10;b) privileges should be allocated to users on a need-to-use basis and on an event-by-event basis in line with the access control policy, i.e. the minimum requirement for their functional role only when needed;&#10;c) an authorization process and a record of all privileges allocated should be maintained. Privileges should not be granted until the authorization process is complete;&#10;d) the development and use of system routines should be promoted to avoid the need to grant privileges to users;&#10;e) the development and use of programs which avoid the need to run with privileges should be promoted;&#10;f) privileges should be assigned to a different user ID from those used for normal business use?","reason":"Formal procedures should be in place to control the allocation of access rights to information systems and services. The procedures should cover all stages in the life-cycle of user access, from the initial registration of new users to the final de-registration of users who no longer require access to information systems and services. Special attention should be given, where appropriate, to the need to control the allocation of privileged access rights, which allow users to override system controls.","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No formal password management process observed.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User password management","question":"Is the allocation of passwords controlled through a formal management process?","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User password management","question":"Does the formal management process include the following requirements:&#10;a) users should be required to sign a statement to keep personal passwords confidential and to keep group passwords solely within the members of the group; this signed statement could be included in the terms and conditions of employment;&#10;b) when users are required to maintain their own passwords they should be provided initially with a secure temporary password, which they are forced to change immediately;&#10;c) establish procedures to verify the identity of a user prior to providing a new, replacement or temporary password;&#10;d) temporary passwords should be given to users in a secure manner; the use of third parties or unprotected (clear text) electronic mail messages should be avoided;&#10;e) temporary passwords should be unique to an individual and should not be guessable;&#10;f) users should acknowledge receipt of passwords;&#10;g) passwords should never be stored on computer systems in an unprotected form;&#10;h) default vendor passwords should be altered following installation of systems or software?","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Username and passwords are used for all systems.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User password management","question":"If appropriate is consideration given to other technologies for user identification and authentication, such as biometrics, (e.g. finger-print verification, signature verification), and use of hardware tokens, (e.g. smart cards)?","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Other than an informal process for PC Lender, did not observe that management reviews access rights.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"customer_response":"Traci - PC Lender user access rights are reviewed regularly.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Review of user access rights","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Does management review users‟ access rights at regular intervals using a formal process?","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":12.5},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Review of user access rights","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for the review of user access rights:&#10;a) users‟ access rights should be reviewed at regular intervals, e.g. a period of 6 months, and after any changes, such as promotion, demotion, or termination of employment;&#10;b) user access rights should be reviewed and re-allocated when moving from one employment to another within the same organization;&#10;c) authorizations for special privileged access rights should be reviewed at more frequent intervals, e.g. at a period of 3 months;&#10;d) privilege allocations should be checked at regular intervals to ensure that unauthorized privileges have not been obtained;&#10;e) changes to privileged accounts should be logged for periodic review?","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Business Sensitive data is stored within PC Lender, One Drive, Drop Box, Google Drive, Sharepoint, etc...\r\n\r\nObserved within PC Lender that business sensitive data is restricted to users with a need to know.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Business Sensitive Information","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Is business sensitive data that is stored on workstations, on web application databases, or on shared folders restricted to users or groups with a need to know?","section":"User access management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":12.5},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Reliant on 3rd party applications to enforce the use of strong passwords (PC Lender, One Drive, Drop Box, Google Drive, Sharepoint, etc...) \r\n\r\nLaptops are not configured with complex password policies.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Password Use","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Are users required to follow good security practices in the selection and use of passwords?","reason":"The co-operation of authorized users is essential for effective security. &#10;&#10;Users should be made aware of their responsibilities for maintaining effective access controls, particularly regarding the use of passwords and the security of user equipment. &#10;&#10;A clear desk and clear screen policy should be implemented to reduce the risk of unauthorized access or damage to papers, media, and information processing facilities.","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":12.5},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Observed that passwords are shared amongst team members.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Password Use","question":"Are all users advised to:&#10;a) keep passwords confidential;&#10;b) avoid keeping a record (e.g. paper, software file or hand-held device) of passwords, unless this can be stored securely and the method of storing has been approved;&#10;c) change passwords whenever there is any indication of possible system or password compromise;&#10;d) select quality passwords with sufficient minimum length which are:&#10;1) easy to remember;&#10;2) not based on anything somebody else could easily guess or obtain using person related information, e.g. names, telephone numbers, and dates of birth etc.;&#10;3) not vulnerable to dictionary attacks (i.e. do not consist of words included in dictionaries);&#10;4) free of consecutive identical, all-numeric or all-alphabetic characters;&#10;e) change passwords at regular intervals or based on the number of accesses (passwords for privileged accounts should be changed more frequently than normal passwords), and avoid re-using or cycling old passwords;&#10;f) change temporary passwords at the first log-on;&#10;g) not include passwords in any automated log-on process, e.g. stored in a macro or function key;&#10;h) not share individual user passwords;&#10;i) not use the same password for business and non-business purposes?","reason":"The co-operation of authorized users is essential for effective security. &#10;&#10;Users should be made aware of their responsibilities for maintaining effective access controls, particularly regarding the use of passwords and the security of user equipment. &#10;&#10;A clear desk and clear screen policy should be implemented to reduce the risk of unauthorized access or damage to papers, media, and information processing facilities.","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"No observed in an policy documents we reviewed.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Password Use","question":"If users need to access multiple services, systems or platforms, and are required to maintain multiple separate passwords, are they advised that they may use a single, quality password for all services where the user is assured that a reasonable level of protection has been established for the storage of the password within each service, system or platform?","reason":"The co-operation of authorized users is essential for effective security. &#10;&#10;Users should be made aware of their responsibilities for maintaining effective access controls, particularly regarding the use of passwords and the security of user equipment. &#10;&#10;A clear desk and clear screen policy should be implemented to reduce the risk of unauthorized access or damage to papers, media, and information processing facilities.","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Not enforced on Laptops via local security policy.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Unattended user equipment","question":"Do users ensure that unattended equipment has appropriate protection (e.g. password locked screen, powered off)?","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Documented in Employee Handbook.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Unattended user equipment","question":"Are all users made aware of the security requirements and procedures for protecting unattended equipment, as well as their responsibilities for implementing such protection?","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Not documented in policies reviewed.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Unattended user equipment","question":"Are users advised to:&#10;a) terminate active sessions when finished, unless they can be secured by an appropriate locking mechanism, e.g. a password protected screen saver;&#10;b) log-off mainframe computers, servers, and office PCs when the session is finished (i.e. not just switch off the PC screen or terminal);&#10;c) secure PCs or terminals from unauthorized use by a key lock or an equivalent control, e.g. password access, when not in use?","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No observed in Employee handbook or IT Procedure Manual","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Clear desk and clear screen policy","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Has a clear desk policy for papers and removable storage media and a clear screen policy for information processing facilities been adopted?","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Clear desk and clear screen policy","question":"Does the clear desk and clear screen policy take into account the information, legal and contractual requirements, and the corresponding risks and cultural aspects of the organization?","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Clear desk and clear screen policy","question":"Are the following guidelines considered regarding a clear desk and clear screen policy:&#10;a) sensitive or critical business information, e.g. on paper or on electronic storage media, should be locked away (ideally in a safe or cabinet or other forms of security furniture) when not required, especially when the office is vacated;&#10;b) computers and terminals should be left logged off or protected with a screen and keyboard locking mechanism controlled by a password, token or similar user authentication mechanism when unattended and should be protected by key locks, passwords or other controls when not in use;&#10;c) incoming and outgoing mail points and unattended facsimile machines should be protected;&#10;d) unauthorized use of photocopiers and other reproduction technology (e.g., scanners, digital cameras) should be prevented; e) documents containing sensitive or classified information should be removed from printers immediately?","section":"User responsibilities","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Policy on use of network services","question":"Are users only provided with access to the network services that they have been specifically authorized to use?","reason":"Access to both internal and external networked services should be controlled. &#10;&#10;User access to networks and network services should not compromise the security of the network services by ensuring: a) appropriate interfaces are in place between the organization‟s network and networks owned by other organizations, and public networks; b) appropriate authentication mechanisms are applied for users and equipment; c) control of user access to information services in enforced.","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"observed in Employee handbook and IT Procedure Manual","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Policy on use of network services","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Has a policy been formulated concerning the use of networks and network services?","reason":"Access to both internal and external networked services should be controlled. &#10;&#10;User access to networks and network services should not compromise the security of the network services by ensuring: a) appropriate interfaces are in place between the organization‟s network and networks owned by other organizations, and public networks; b) appropriate authentication mechanisms are applied for users and equipment; c) control of user access to information services in enforced.","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Policy on use of network services","question":"Does this policy cover:&#10;a) the networks and network services which are allowed to be accessed;&#10;b) authorization procedures for determining who is allowed to access which networks and networked services;&#10;c) management controls and procedures to protect access to network connections and network services;&#10;d) the means used to access networks and network services (e.g. the conditions for allowing dial-up access to an internet service provider or remote system).","reason":"Access to both internal and external networked services should be controlled. &#10;&#10;User access to networks and network services should not compromise the security of the network services by ensuring: a) appropriate interfaces are in place between the organization‟s network and networks owned by other organizations, and public networks; b) appropriate authentication mechanisms are applied for users and equipment; c) control of user access to information services in enforced.","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Policy on use of network services","question":"Is the policy on the use of network services consistent with the business access control policy?","reason":"Access to both internal and external networked services should be controlled. &#10;&#10;User access to networks and network services should not compromise the security of the network services by ensuring: a) appropriate interfaces are in place between the organization‟s network and networks owned by other organizations, and public networks; b) appropriate authentication mechanisms are applied for users and equipment; c) control of user access to information services in enforced.","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Remote access through SonicWALL devices utilizes username/password over an encrypted session.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User authentication for external connections","question":"Are appropriate authentication methods used to control access by remote users?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User authentication for external connections","question":"When using this control, does the organization prohibit the use of network services, which include call forwarding, or, if they do not prohibit the use, do they disable the use of such features to avoid&#10;weaknesses associated with call forwarding?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User authentication for external connections","question":"Does the call back process ensure that an actual disconnection on the organization's side occurs?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User authentication for external connections","question":"Are call back procedures and controls thoroughly tested for this possibility?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Using WPA-2 personal.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User authentication for external connections","question":"Are additional authentication controls implemented to control access to wireless networks?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Equipment identification in networks","question":"Is automatic equipment identification considered as a means to authenticate connections from specific locations and equipment?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No MAC address filtering.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Equipment identification in networks","question":"Are identifiers, in or attached to equipment, used to indicate whether equipment is permitted to connect to the network?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Equipment identification in networks","question":"If used do these identifiers, in or attached to equipment, clearly indicate to which network the equipment is permitted to connect?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Physical access to configuration ports are controlled.   Logical control - Management VLANs can still traverse their production VLANs.","control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Remote diagnostic and configuration port protection","question":"Is physical and logical access to diagnostic and configuration ports controlled?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":18.75},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Identified some services that weren't required on laptops.   Applications on laptops were for business purposes though.","control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Remote diagnostic and configuration port protection","question":"Are ports, services, and similar facilities installed on a computer or network facility, which are not specifically required for business functionality, disabled or removed?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":18.75},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"VLAN separation is not implemented between business units or management and production networks.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Segregation in networks","question":"Are groups of information services, users, and information systems segregated on networks?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Segregation in networks","question":"If separate logical network domains, (e.g. an organization‟s internal network domains and external network domains), are defined, are they defined based on a risk assessment and the different security requirements within each of the domains?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"There is no access control policy.       Some outbound traffic filtering exists between the corporate network and the internet.  inbound policies are also in place to restrict information flow between the internet and the corporate network.","control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Segregation in networks","question":"If a secure gateway (commonly referred to as a firewall) is installed between the two networks to be interconnected to control access and information flow between the two domains, configured to filter traffic between these domains and to block unauthorized access in accordance with the organization‟s access control policy?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":12.5},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"There is no network separation between business entities   (Movement Title and Movement Mortgage).","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Segregation in networks","question":"Is the criteria for segregation of networks into domains based on the access control policy and access requirements, and also take account of the relative cost and performance impact of incorporating suitable network routing or gateway technology?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Segregation in networks","question":"Is segregation of networks based on the value and classification of information stored or processed in the network, levels of trust, or lines of business, in order to reduce the total impact of a service disruption?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Consideration was given, but implementation was not proper.","control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Segregation in networks","question":"Is consideration given to the segregation of wireless networks from internal and private networks?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Segregation in networks","question":"As the perimeters of wireless networks are not well defined, is a risk assessment carried out in such cases to identify controls (e.g. strong authentication, cryptographic methods, and frequency selection) to maintain network segregation?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network connection control","question":"For shared networks, especially those extending across the organization‟s boundaries, is the capability of users to connect to the network restricted, in line with the access control policy and requirements of the business applications?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No access Control Policy.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network connection control","question":"Is the network access rights of users maintained and updated as required by the access control policy?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Only firewall rules implemented were to block MS updates, Hulu, and Netflix for QoS purposes.\r\n\r\nMinimal web-application filter was implemented.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network connection control","question":"Is consideration given to restricting the connection capability of users through network gateways that filter traffic by means of pre-defined tables or rules for the following applications:&#10;a) messaging, e.g. electronic mail;&#10;b) file transfer;&#10;c) interactive access;&#10;d) application access?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network connection control","question":"Is linking network access rights to certain times of day or dates considered?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No access control policy.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network routing control","question":"Are routing controls implemented where required by the access control policy of the business applications?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network routing control","question":"Are routing controls based on positive source and destination address checking mechanisms?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network routing control","question":"Are implementers aware of the strengths and shortcomings of any security gateways used to validate source and destination addresses at internal and external network control points if proxy and/or network address translation technologies are employed?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Network routing control","question":"Are requirements for network routing control based on the access control policy?","section":"Network Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Username and password is required.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Secure log-on procedures","question":"Is access to operating systems controlled by a secure log-on procedure?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to operating systems to authorized users. &#10;&#10;The facilities should be capable of the following:&#10;a) authenticating authorized users, in accordance with a defined access control policy; &#10;b) recording successful and failed system authentication attempts; &#10;c) recording the use of special system privileges; &#10;d) issuing alarms when system security policies are breached; &#10;e) providing appropriate means for authentication; &#10;f) where appropriate, restricting the connection time of users.","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No password or lockout policies were in place","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Secure log-on procedures","question":"Is the procedure for logging into an operating system designed to minimize the opportunity for unauthorized access?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to operating systems to authorized users. &#10;&#10;The facilities should be capable of the following:&#10;a) authenticating authorized users, in accordance with a defined access control policy; &#10;b) recording successful and failed system authentication attempts; &#10;c) recording the use of special system privileges; &#10;d) issuing alarms when system security policies are breached; &#10;e) providing appropriate means for authentication; &#10;f) where appropriate, restricting the connection time of users.","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Secure log-on procedures","question":"Does the log-on procedure disclose the minimum of information&#10;about the system, in order to avoid providing an unauthorized user with any unnecessary assistance?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to operating systems to authorized users. &#10;&#10;The facilities should be capable of the following:&#10;a) authenticating authorized users, in accordance with a defined access control policy; &#10;b) recording successful and failed system authentication attempts; &#10;c) recording the use of special system privileges; &#10;d) issuing alarms when system security policies are breached; &#10;e) providing appropriate means for authentication; &#10;f) where appropriate, restricting the connection time of users.","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Secure log-on procedures","question":"Is consideration given to the following steps and implemented where appropriate for secure log-on:&#10;a) not display system or application identifiers until the log-on process has been successfully completed;&#10;b) display a general notice warning that the computer should only be accessed by authorized users;&#10;c) not provide help messages during the log-on procedure that would aid an unauthorized user;&#10;d) validate the log-on information only on completion of all input data. If an error condition arises, the system should not indicate which part of the data is correct or incorrect;&#10;e) limit the number of unsuccessful log-on attempts allowed, e.g. to three attempts, and consider:&#10;1) recording unsuccessful and successful attempts;&#10;2) forcing a time delay before further log-on attempts are allowed or rejecting any further attempts without specific authorization;&#10;3) disconnecting data link connections;&#10;4) sending an alarm message to the system console if the maximum number of log-on attempts is reached;&#10;5) setting the number of password retries in conjunction with the minimum length of the password and the value of the system being protected;&#10;f) limit the maximum and minimum time allowed for the log-on procedure. If exceeded, the system should terminate the log-on;&#10;g) display the following information on completion of a successful log-on:&#10;1) date and time of the previous successful log-on;&#10;2) details of any unsuccessful log-on attempts since the last successful log-on;&#10;h) not display the password being entered or consider hiding the password characters by symbols;&#10;i) not transmit passwords in clear text over a network?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to operating systems to authorized users. &#10;&#10;The facilities should be capable of the following:&#10;a) authenticating authorized users, in accordance with a defined access control policy; &#10;b) recording successful and failed system authentication attempts; &#10;c) recording the use of special system privileges; &#10;d) issuing alarms when system security policies are breached; &#10;e) providing appropriate means for authentication; &#10;f) where appropriate, restricting the connection time of users.","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Yes on laptops, no on network devices (Sonic Walls).","control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Do all users have a unique identifier (user ID) for their personal use only?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":18.75},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Username/password.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Has a suitable authentication technique been chosen to substantiate the claimed identity of a user?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Auditing is not completly implemented on all devices.  Additionally, audit logs are not reviewed on a regular basis.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Are user IDs used to trace activities to the responsible individual?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Are regular user activities performed from privileged accounts? (NOTE: Yes is a bad answer here.)","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Shared accounts are in use, but there is no documentation on the requirement.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Is approval by management documented for exceptional circumstances, where there is a clear business benefit, to allow the use of a shared user ID for a group of users or a specific job?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Are generic IDs for use by an individual allowed either where the functions accessible or actions carried out by the ID do not need to be traced (e.g. read only access), or where there are other controls in place (e.g. password for a generic ID only issued to one staff at a time and logging such instance)?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Are authentication methods alternative to passwords, such as cryptographic means, smart cards, tokens or biometric means, used where strong authentication and identity verification is required?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"User identification and authentication","question":"Is the strength of user identification and authentication suitable to the sensitivity of the information to be accessed?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"No for Windows systems.","control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Password management system","question":"Are systems for managing passwords interactive and so they ensure quality passwords?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":12.5},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"No on Windows Systems.","control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Password management system","question":"Is consideration given to the following items and implemented where appropriate for password management:&#10;a) enforce the use of individual user IDs and passwords to maintain accountability;&#10;b) allow users to select and change their own passwords and include a confirmation procedure to allow for input errors;&#10;c) enforce a choice of quality passwords;&#10;d) enforce password changes;&#10;e) force users to change temporary passwords at the first log-on;&#10;f) maintain a record of previous user passwords and prevent re-use;&#10;g) not display passwords on the screen when being entered;&#10;h) store password files separately from application system data;&#10;i) store and transmit passwords in protected (e.g. encrypted or hashed) form?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":12.5},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"UAC implemented on Windows laptops.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Use of system utilities","question":"Is the use of utility programs that might be capable of overriding system and application controls restricted and tightly controlled?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Use of system utilities","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for system utilities:&#10;a) use of identification, authentication, and authorization procedures for system utilities;&#10;b) segregation of system utilities from applications software;&#10;c) limitation of the use of system utilities to the minimum practical number of trusted, authorized users;&#10;d) authorization for ad hoc use of systems utilities;&#10;e) limitation of the availability of system utilities, e.g. for the duration of an authorized change;&#10;f) logging of all use of system utilities;&#10;g) defining and documenting of authorization levels for system utilities;&#10;h) removal or disabling of all unnecessary software based utilities and system software;&#10;i) not making system utilities available to users who have access to applications on systems where segregation of duties is required?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Windows laptops audited failed inactivity timer set.   This was defined on network devices, but the inactivity period was very long on some devices (switches were 60 minutes).","control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Session time-out","question":"Are inactive sessions shut down after a defined period of inactivity?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":12.5},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Session time-out","question":"Does the time-out facility clear the session screen and also, possibly later, close both application and network sessions after a defined period of inactivity?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Session time-out","question":"Does the time-out delay reflect the security risks of the area, the classification of the information being handled and the applications being used, and the risks related to the users of the equipment?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Session time-out","question":"Are the sessions shut down to prevent access by unauthorized persons and denial of service attacks?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Limitation of connection time","question":"Are restrictions on connection times used to provide additional security for high-risk applications?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Limitation of connection time","question":"Are connection time controls considered for sensitive computer applications, especially from high risk locations, e.g. public or external areas that are outside the organization‟s security management?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Limitation of connection time","question":"Is consideration given to the following restrictions for limiting the connection time:&#10;a) using predetermined time slots, e.g. for batch file transmissions, or regular interactive sessions of short duration;&#10;b) restricting connection times to normal office hours if there is no requirement for overtime or extended-hours operation;&#10;c) considering re-authentication at timed intervals?","section":"Operating System Access Control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No access control policy.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Information access restriction","question":"Is access to information and application system functions by users and support personnel restricted in accordance with the defined access control policy?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to and within application systems. Logical access to application software and information should be restricted to authorized users. Application systems should: a) control user access to information and application system functions, in accordance with a defined access control policy; b) provide protection from unauthorized access by any utility, operating system software, and malicious software that is capable of overriding or bypassing system or application controls; c) not compromise other systems with which information resources are shared.","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Yes for PC Lender, but no formal policy.","control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"customer_response":"","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Information access restriction","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Are restrictions to access based on individual business application requirements?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to and within application systems. Logical access to application software and information should be restricted to authorized users. Application systems should: a) control user access to information and application system functions, in accordance with a defined access control policy; b) provide protection from unauthorized access by any utility, operating system software, and malicious software that is capable of overriding or bypassing system or application controls; c) not compromise other systems with which information resources are shared.","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":25},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Information access restriction","question":"Is the access control policy also consistent with the organizational access policy?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to and within application systems. Logical access to application software and information should be restricted to authorized users. Application systems should: a) control user access to information and application system functions, in accordance with a defined access control policy; b) provide protection from unauthorized access by any utility, operating system software, and malicious software that is capable of overriding or bypassing system or application controls; c) not compromise other systems with which information resources are shared.","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Information access restriction","question":"Is consideration given to the following guidelines and implemented where appropriate for information access restriction:&#10;a) providing menus to control access to application system functions;&#10;b) controlling the access rights of users, e.g. read, write, delete, and execute;&#10;c) controlling access rights of other applications;&#10;d) ensuring that outputs from application systems handling sensitive information contain only the information relevant to the use of the output and are sent only to authorized terminals and locations; this should include periodic reviews of such outputs to ensure that redundant information is removed?","reason":"Security facilities should be used to restrict access to and within application systems. Logical access to application software and information should be restricted to authorized users. Application systems should: a) control user access to information and application system functions, in accordance with a defined access control policy; b) provide protection from unauthorized access by any utility, operating system software, and malicious software that is capable of overriding or bypassing system or application controls; c) not compromise other systems with which information resources are shared.","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Sensitive system isolation","question":"Do sensitive systems have a dedicated (isolated) computing environment?","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Sensitive system isolation","question":"Are the following points considered for sensitive system isolation:&#10;a) the sensitivity of an application system should be explicitly identified and documented by the application owner;&#10;b) when a sensitive application is to run in a shared environment, the application systems with which it will share resources and the corresponding risks should be identified and accepted by the owner of the sensitive application?","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Sensitive system isolation","question":"Are any of the application systems sufficiently sensitive to potential loss that they require special handling?","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Sensitive system isolation","question":"If any of the application systems are sufficiently sensitive to potential loss that they require special handling has consideration been given to whether they:&#10;a) should run on a dedicated computer; or&#10;b) should only share resources with trusted applications systems.","section":"Application and information access control","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Does the organization have a formal policy in place?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Good for Enterprise is deployed, but settings are all defaults.   Not deployed to all users as well.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Are appropriate security measures adopted to protect against the risks of using mobile computing and communication assets?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No data at rest encryption is deployed on laptops.  Laptops and mobile devices are not security hardened.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Is special care taken to ensure that business information is not compromised when using mobile computing and communicating assets, (e.g. notebooks, palmtops, laptops, smart cards, and mobile phones)?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Does the mobile computing policy take into account the risks of working with mobile computing equipment in unprotected environments?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Does the mobile computing policy include the requirements for physical protection, access controls, cryptographic techniques, back-ups, and virus protection?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Does the mobile computing policy also include rules and advice on connecting mobile assets to networks and guidance on the use of these assets in public places?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Is care taken when using mobile computing assets in public places, meeting rooms and other unprotected areas outside of the organization‟s premises?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Is protection in place to avoid the unauthorized access to or disclosure of the information stored and processed by these assets, e.g. using cryptographic techniques?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Do users of mobile computing assets in public places take care to avoid the risk of overlooking by unauthorized persons?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Does remote access to business information across public network using mobile computing assets only take place after successful identification and authentication, and with suitable access control mechanisms in place?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Is training arranged for personnel using mobile computing to raise their awareness on the additional risks resulting from this way of working and the controls that should be implemented?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Mobile computing and communications","question":"Are the following points considered for mobile network wireless connections when identifying controls:&#10;a) some wireless security protocols are immature and have known weaknesses;&#10;b) information stored on mobile computers may not be backed-up because of limited network bandwidth and/or because mobile equipment may not be connected at the times when back-ups are scheduled?","reason":"The protection required should be commensurate with the risks these specific ways of working cause. When using mobile computing the risks of working in an unprotected environment should be considered and appropriate protection applied.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Teleworking","question":"Has a policy, operational plans and procedures been developed and implemented for teleworking activities?","reason":"The organization should apply protection to the teleworking site and ensure that suitable arrangements are in place for this way of working.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Teleworking","question":"Has the organization authorized teleworking activities, only after they are satisfied that appropriate security arrangements and controls are in place, and that these comply with the organization‟s security policy?","reason":"The organization should apply protection to the teleworking site and ensure that suitable arrangements are in place for this way of working.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Teleworking","question":"Is suitable protection of the teleworking site in place against, e.g., the theft of equipment and information, the unauthorized disclosure of information, unauthorized remote access to the organization‟s internal systems or misuse of facilities?","reason":"The organization should apply protection to the teleworking site and ensure that suitable arrangements are in place for this way of working.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Teleworking","question":"Has teleworking activities been authorized and controlled by management, and is it ensured that suitable arrangements are in place for this way of working?","reason":"The organization should apply protection to the teleworking site and ensure that suitable arrangements are in place for this way of working.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Teleworking","question":"Has consideration been given to the following matters:&#10;a) the existing physical security of the teleworking site, taking into account the physical security of the building and the local environment;&#10;b) the proposed physical teleworking environment;&#10;c) the communications security requirements, taking into account the need for remote access to the organization‟s internal systems, the sensitivity of the information that will be accessed and pass over the communication link and the sensitivity of the internal system;&#10;d) the threat of unauthorized access to information or resources from other persons using the accommodation, e.g. family and friends;&#10;e) the use of home networks and requirements or restrictions on the configuration of wireless network services;&#10;f) policies and procedures to prevent disputes concerning rights to intellectual property developed on privately owned equipment;&#10;g) access to privately owned equipment (to check the security of the machine or during an investigation), which may be prevented by legislation;&#10;h) software licensing agreements that are such that organizations may become liable for licensing for client software on workstations owned privately by employees, contractors or third party users;&#10;i) anti-virus protection and firewall requirements.","reason":"The organization should apply protection to the teleworking site and ensure that suitable arrangements are in place for this way of working.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Teleworking","question":"Has consideration been given to the following guidelines and arrangements:&#10;a) the provision of suitable equipment and storage furniture for the teleworking activities, where the use of privately owned equipment that is not under the control of the organization is not allowed;&#10;b) a definition of the work permitted, the hours of work, the classification of information that may be held and the internal systems and services that the teleworker is authorized to access;&#10;c) the provision of suitable communication equipment, including methods for securing remote access;&#10;d) physical security;&#10;e) rules and guidance on family and visitor access to equipment and information;&#10;f) the provision of hardware and software support and maintenance;&#10;g) the provision of insurance;&#10;h) the procedures for back-up and business continuity;&#10;i) audit and security monitoring;&#10;j) revocation of authority and access rights, and the return of equipment when the teleworking activities are terminated.","reason":"The organization should apply protection to the teleworking site and ensure that suitable arrangements are in place for this way of working.","section":"Mobile computing and teleworking","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Yes within PC Lender.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Personally Identifiable Information (PII)","question":"Whether customer data stored locally on workstations, on web application databases,  or on shared folders is restricted to users or groups with a need to know.","section":"Data Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC; (§ 6801(b), Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA))","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Data Access Auditing","question":"Whether audit logging for access to nonpublic and business sensitive data is enabled on shared folders.","section":"Data Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Detection/Notification on failed access","question":"Whether the system can detect attempts by users to access files on local systems or on shared folders without appropriate permissions.  Whether the system an generate an alert or email to administrative personnel when a user inappropriately accesses a file share.","section":"Data Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Account Review","question":"Whether user accounts are reviewed and disabled if the account cannot be associated with a business process and owner.","section":"Account Monitoring and Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Account Reporting","question":"Whether reports are created that include a list of locked-out accounts, disabled accounts, accounts with passwords that exceed the maximum password age, and accounts with passwords that never expire. This list should be sent to the associated system administrator in a secure fashion","section":"Account Monitoring and Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Informal process managed through emails and not a formal automated ticket system.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Account Revocation","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Whether a process for revoking system access by disabling accounts immediately upon termination of an employee or contractor exists. Disabling instead of deleting accounts allows preservation of audit trails.","section":"Account Monitoring and Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No enforced on laptops","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Password Policy","question":"Whether it is required that all non-administrator accounts have strong passwords that contain letters, numbers, and special characters, be changed at least every 90 days, have a minimal age of one day, and not be allowed to use the previous 15 passwords as a new password. These values can be adjusted based on the specific business needs of the organization.","section":"Account Monitoring and Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Not enforced on laptops","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Account Lockout","question":"Use and configure account lockouts such that after a set number of failed login attempts the account is locked for a standard period of time.","section":"Account Monitoring and Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Not configured on laptops to lock the screen within 15 minutes of inactivity.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Screen Lock","question":"Whether screen locks are configured on systems to limit access to unattended workstations.","section":"Account Monitoring and Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Software identification on the network","question":"Whether software on computing assets are actively managed (inventory, track, and correct) so that only authorized software is installed and can execute, and that unauthorized and unmanaged software is found and prevented from installation or execution. SW inventory scanning?","section":"Software access control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Wireless Access Policy","question":"Where a specific business need for wireless access has been identified, configure wireless access on client machines to allow access only to authorized wireless networks.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Authorized Wireless Devices","question":"Whether each wireless device connected to the network matches an authorized device in the hardware inventory with a documented owner and a defined business need.   ","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Wireless Access Point Scanning","question":"Whether network vulnerability scanning tools have been configured to detect wireless access points connected to the wired network. Identified devices should be reconciled against a list of authorized wireless access points. Unauthorized (i.e., rogue) access points should be deactivated.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Wireless Intrusion Detection System","question":"Whether a wireless intrusion detection systems (WIDS) is used to identify rogue wireless devices and detect attack attempts and successful compromises. In addition to WIDS, all wireless traffic should be monitored by WIDS as traffic passes into the wired network.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Disable Wireless capability","question":"For devices that do not have an essential wireless business purpose, disable wireless access in the hardware configuration (basic input/output system or extensible firmware interface), with password protections to lower the possibility that the user will override such configurations.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Default OFF setting on wireless interfaces","question":"Whether laptops with WLAN interfaces have the WLAN card radio set to OFF as the default setting.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Automatic connections to wireless networks","question":"Whether WLAN clients are configured to connect to other WLAN devices without the user initiating a request to establish such a connection.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Simultaneous use of wired and wireless interfaces","question":"Whether a device’s wired network interfaces (e.g., Ethernet) are disconnected or otherwise disabled when wireless connections are in use.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"WPA Personal","domain":"Access Control","objective":"Encryption of Wireless Traffic","question":"Does all wireless traffic leverages at least Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) encryption used with at least Wi-Fi Protected Access 2 (WPA2) protection?","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Peer-to-Peer Wireless","question":"Whether peer-to-peer wireless network capabilities on wireless clients has been disabled, unless such functionality meets a documented business need.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Access Control","objective":"Wireless Peripheral Access","question":"Has wireless access (such as Bluetooth) of peripheral devices been disabled, unless such access is required for a documented business need?","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Personal cell phones were found on the production wireless network during scans.","domain":"Access Control","objective":"VLAN Separation of Wireless devices","question":"Have separate VLANs been created for BYOD systems or other untrusted devices?  Enterprise access from this VLAN should be treated as untrusted and filtered and audited accordingly.","section":"Wireless Access Control","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No automated vulnerability scanning tools implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Automated Vulnerability Scanning","question":"Whether automated vulnerability scanning tools are run against all systems on the network on a weekly or more frequent basis and deliver prioritized lists of the most critical vulnerabilities to each responsible system administrator along with risk scores that compare the effectiveness of system administrators and departments in reducing risk.","section":"Continuous Vulnerability Assessment and Remediation","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No vulnerability scanning tools implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Authenticated Vulnerability Scanning","question":"Whether vulnerability scanning is performed in authenticated mode either with agents running locally on each end system to analyze the security configuration or with remote scanners that are given administrative rights on the system being tested. ","section":"Continuous Vulnerability Assessment and Remediation","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No automated patch management tools or software update tools implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Automated Patch Management","question":"Whether automated patch management tools and software update tools have been deployed for operating system and software/applications on all systems for which such tools are available and safe. Patches should be applied to all systems, even systems that are properly air gapped.","section":"Continuous Vulnerability Assessment and Remediation","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No vulnerability intelligence services implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Vulnerability Awareness / Updates","question":"Subscribe to vulnerability intelligence services in order to stay aware of emerging exposures, and use the information gained from this subscription to update the organization's vulnerability scanning activities on at least a monthly basis. Alternatively, ensure that the vulnerability scanning tools you use are regularly updated with all relevant important security vulnerabilities.","section":"Continuous Vulnerability Assessment and Remediation","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No evidence of available vulnerability scan results.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Vulnerability Remediation","question":"Compare the results from back-to-back vulnerability scans to verify that vulnerabilities were addressed either by patching, implementing a compensating control, or documenting and accepting a reasonable business risk. Such acceptance of business risks for existing vulnerabilities should be periodically reviewed to determine if newer compensating controls or subsequent patches can address vulnerabilities that were previously accepted, or if conditions have changed, increasing the risk.","section":"Continuous Vulnerability Assessment and Remediation","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No automated tools to manage security services.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Enterprise Antivirus & Anti-malware Management","question":"Whether automated tools to continuously monitor workstations, servers, and mobile devices with anti-virus, anti-spyware, personal firewalls, and host-based IPS functionality have been employed. All malware detection events should be sent to enterprise anti-malware administration tools and event log servers.","section":"Antivirus and Antimalware prevention and detection","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No centralized infrastructure for anti-malware software.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Centralized Update Management","question":"Employ anti-malware software that offers a centralized infrastructure that compiles information on file reputations or have administrators manually push updates to all machines. After applying an update, automated systems should verify that each system has received its signature update.","section":"Antivirus and Antimalware prevention and detection","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Auto-run discovered to be enabled on multiple audited devices.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Disable Auto-run from removable media","question":"Configure laptops, workstations, and servers so that they will not auto-run content from removable media, like USB tokens (i.e., \"thumb drives\"), USB hard drives, CDs/DVDs, FireWire devices, external serial advanced technology attachment devices, and mounted network shares,.","section":"Antivirus and Antimalware prevention and detection","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Assessed based on default Microsoft Defender settings.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Auto-scan of Removable Media","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Whether systems are configured so that they automatically conduct an anti-malware scan of removable media when inserted.","section":"Antivirus and Antimalware prevention and detection","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":25},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Implemented by Office 365.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Email attachment scanning","question":"Scan and block all e-mail attachments entering the organization's e-mail gateway if they contain malicious code or file types that are unnecessary for the organization's business. This scanning should be done before the e-mail is placed in the user's inbox. This includes e-mail content filtering and web content filtering.","section":"Antivirus and Antimalware prevention and detection","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"USB flash drives allowed read-only access. No access control for external devices.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"External Device Usage & Monitoring","question":"Whether the use of external devices is limited to those that have a business need. Monitor for use and attempted use of external devices.","section":"Antivirus and Antimalware prevention and detection","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Secure configuration assessment revealed unnecessary services, open network ports, missing patches, and unsecure local group policy settings.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Operating System hardening","question":"Whether the operating system is security hardened prior to assignment to the end user.  Hardening typically includes: removal of unnecessary accounts (including service accounts), disabling or removal of unnecessary services, configuring non-executable stacks and heaps, applying patches, closing open and unused network ports, implementing intrusion detection systems and/or intrusion prevention systems, and use of host-based firewalls.","section":"Secure Configuration of laptops, workstations, and servers","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No automated patching tools and processes implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Automated software updating","question":"Whether automated patching tools and processes for both applications and for operating system software have been implemented. When outdated systems can no longer be patched, update to the latest version of application software. Remove outdated, older, and unused software from the system.","section":"Secure Configuration of laptops, workstations, and servers","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Secure Remote administration","question":"Does remote administration of servers, workstation, network devices, and similar equipment over secure channels?  Protocols such as telnet, VNC, RDP, or others that do not actively support strong encryption should only be used if they are performed over a secondary encryption channel, such as SSL or IPSEC.","section":"Secure Configuration of laptops, workstations, and servers","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No file integrity checking tools implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"File Integrity Checking","question":"Whether file integrity checking tools are utilized to ensure that critical system files (including sensitive system and application executables, libraries, and configurations) have not been altered. All alterations to such files should be automatically reported security personnel. The reporting system should have the ability to account for routine and expected changes, highlighting unusual or unexpected alterations.","section":"Secure Configuration of laptops, workstations, and servers","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No BIOS passwords implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"System BIOS or system controllers Password Set","question":"System BIOS or system controllers supporting password protection must have administrator accounts/passwords configured, and no others.","section":"Secure Configuration of laptops, workstations, and servers","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Booting from removable media was not enabled on audited device, although lack of BIOS password allowed any user to enable this feature.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Boot from removable media","question":"Whether the system is configured to not use removable media as the boot loader","section":"Secure Configuration of laptops, workstations, and servers","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No centralized system configuration management tools implemented such as Active Directory.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"System Configuration Management Tools","question":"Whether system configuration management tools (such as Active Directory Group Policy Objects) are utilized that will automatically enforce and redeploy configuration settings to systems at regularly scheduled intervals.","section":"Secure Configuration of laptops, workstations, and servers","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No standard secure configurations available for network devices.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Secure Configuration","question":"Compare firewall, router, and switch configuration against standard secure configurations defined for each type of network device in use in the organization.   Any deviations from the standard configuration or updates to the standard configuration should be documented and approved in a change control system.","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No network diagrams available.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Network Diagram","question":"Whether a network diagram is maintained that identifies all network connections within the environment and to other networks, including any wireless networks.  Without current network diagrams, devices could &#10;be overlooked and be unknowingly left out of implemented security controls. Whether a network diagram is maintained that identifies all network connections within the environment and to other networks, including any wireless networks.  Without current network diagrams, devices could &#10;be overlooked and be unknowingly left out of implemented security controls.","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No configuration management plan, process, or tracking system for network device configuration changes.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Documented Configuration Rules","question":"All new configuration rules beyond a baseline-hardened configuration that allow traffic to flow through network security devices, such as firewalls and network-based IPS, should be documented and recorded in a configuration management system, with a specific business reason for each change, a specific individual's name responsible for that business need, and an expected duration of the need.","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No policy exists for periodic review of network device configurations.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Configuration Review","question":"Whether network device configurations (router/firewall rulesets) are reviewed at least every six months to clean up any unneeded, outdated or incorrect rules, and ensure that the rulesets allow only authorized ports and services that match business justifications.","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"SonicWALL configuration only stored on the device. Note that shared accounts are used for network devices.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Secure and synchronize router &#10;configuration filesSecure and synchronize router &#10;configuration files","question":"Whether network device configuration files (router/firewall rulesets) are secured from unauthorized access.  Whether these configuration files are synchronized (running config matches startup config on a router) ","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Two-factor authentication not implemented. Score 50%","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Session Security","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Whether network devices are managed using two-factor authentication and encrypted sessions.","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":25},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"SonicWALL automatically installs security updates. Layer 2 switches not automated.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":2,"text":"Automated on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Software Updates","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Whether automated tools are used to apply the latest stable version of any security-related update to network devices.","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No out-of-band management implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Management VLAN","question":"Manage the network infrastructure across network connections that are separated from the business use of that network, relying on separate VLANs or, preferably, on entirely different physical connectivity for management sessions for network devices.","section":"Secure Configurations for Network Devices ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Default ports, protocols, and services enabled on audited devices. Unsecured wireless access point discovered. Printers shared from user workstations.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Limit PPS on each system","question":"Ensure that only ports, protocols, and services with validated business needs are running on each networked asset.","section":"Limitation and Control of Network Ports, Protocols, and Services","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Host-based firewalls on user systems do not block unknown outgoing traffic.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Host-Based Firewall","question":"Apply host-based firewalls or port filtering tools on end systems, with a default-deny rule that drops all traffic except those services and ports that are explicitly allowed.","section":"Limitation and Control of Network Ports, Protocols, and Services","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No automated port scans performed on a regular basis.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Automated Port Scanning","question":"Perform automated port scans on a regular basis against all networked assets and compared to a known effective baseline. If a change that is not listed on the organization's approved baseline is discovered, an alert should be generated and reviewed.","section":"Limitation and Control of Network Ports, Protocols, and Services","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Service Minimization","question":"Keep all services up to date and uninstall and remove any unnecessary components from the system.","section":"Limitation and Control of Network Ports, Protocols, and Services","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"End user laptops did not have administrative privileges, but IT staff used administrative accounts for servers and network devices.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Administrator Privilege Use & Monitoring","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Minimize administrative privileges and only use administrative accounts when they are required. Implement focused auditing on the use of administrative privileged functions and monitor for anomalous behavior.","section":"Controlled Use of Administrative Privileges","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":16.666666666666664},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No automated tools to inventory administrative accounts.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Administrative Account Inventory","question":"Use automated tools to inventory all administrative accounts and validate that each person with administrative privileges on desktops, laptops, and servers is authorized by a manager.","section":"Controlled Use of Administrative Privileges","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Administrative password complexity policy not enforced.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Password complexity","question":"Configure all administrative passwords to be complex and contain letters, numbers, and special characters intermixed, and with no dictionary words present in the password. Pass phrases containing multiple dictionary words, along with special characters, are acceptable if they are of a reasonable length.","section":"Controlled Use of Administrative Privileges","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Printers had no passwords set.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":2,"text":"Implemented on Some Systems","value":0.5},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Default Administrator Passwords","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Before deploying any new devices in a networked environment, change all default passwords for applications, operating systems, routers, firewalls, wireless access points, and other systems to have values consistent with administration-level accounts. This also includes things like default SNMP community strings.","section":"Controlled Use of Administrative Privileges","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Mobile devices, laptops and printers did not have hard drive encryption or similar security features implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Hard Drive Encryption","question":"Whether an approved hard drive encryption software is deployed to mobile devices and systems that store sensitive data.","section":"Data Protection ","source":"SANS 20 CSC; (§ 6801(b), Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA))","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Brett Rodgers -  Our Loan Originiation Software provider has not responded to requests for this kind of information.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Cloud Provider Security","question":"Whether cloud provider security practices for data protection have been reviewed.  PC Lender? Dropbox?  Exchange?","section":"Data Protection ","source":"SANS 20 CSC; (§ 6801(b), Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA))","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"PCLender, Dropbox, and Office 365 use secure, authenticated, and encrypted mechanisms.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Data in transit","question":"Whether data moved between networks is transmitted using secure, authenticated, and encrypted mechanisms.","section":"Data Protection ","source":"SANS 20 CSC; (§ 103(a)(2)(A)(iii)(II)(bb), The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 (SOX))","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Observed laptop could not write to a USB flash drive.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"No Write to USB Devices","question":"If there is no business need for supporting such devices, configure systems so that they will not write data to USB tokens or USB hard drives. If such devices are required, enterprise software should be used that can configure systems to allow only specific USB devices (based on serial number or other unique property) to be accessed, and that can automatically encrypt all data placed on such devices. An inventory of all authorized devices must be maintained.","section":"Data Protection ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No log repository for review of outgoing traffic. Reliant on SonicWALL signatures for detection of unauthorized use of encryption.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Network Traffic Monitoring","question":"Monitor all traffic leaving the organization and detect any unauthorized use of encryption. Attackers often use an encrypted channel to bypass network security devices. Therefore it is essential that organizations be able to detect rogue connections, terminate the connection, and remediate the infected system.","section":"Data Protection ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No website blocking implemented for these types of websites.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"External Websites","question":"Whether access to known file transfer and email exfiltration websites is blocked.","section":"Data Protection ","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Reliant on SonicWALL signatures.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"IP Address Blacklisting/Whitelisting","question":"Deny communications with (or limit data flow to) known malicious IP addresses (black lists), or limit access only to trusted sites (whitelists). Tests can be periodically carried out by sending packets from bogus source IP addresses (non-routable or otherwise unused IP addresses) into the network to verify that they are not transmitted through network perimeters. Lists of bogon IP addresses are publicly available on the Internet from various sources, and indicate a series of IP addresses that should not be used for legitimate traffic traversing the Internet.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Need more information about Azure deployment and architecture.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Firewall Implementation","question":"Whether a firewall is implemented at each internet connection and between any DMZ and the internal network zone.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"auditor_notes":"No DMZ","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"DMZ Traffic Monitoring","question":"On DMZ networks, configure monitoring systems (which may be built in to the IDS sensors or deployed as a separate technology) to record at least packet header information, and preferably full packet header and payloads of the traffic destined for or passing through the network border. This traffic should be sent to a properly configured Security Information Event Management (SIEM) or log analytics system so that events can be correlated from all devices on the network.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"SonicWALL IDS features enabled.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Network-based IDS","question":"Deploy network-based IDS sensors on Internet and extranet DMZ systems and networks that look for unusual attack mechanisms and detect compromise of these systems. These network-based IDS sensors may detect attacks through the use of signatures, network behavior analysis, or other mechanisms to analyze traffic.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"SonicWALL IPS features enabled.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Network-based IDS Blocking of bad traffic","question":"Network-based IPS devices should be deployed to complement IDS by blocking known bad signature or behavior of attacks. As attacks become automated, methods such as IDS typically delay the amount of time it takes for someone to react to an attack. A properly configured network-based IPS can provide automation to block bad traffic. When evaluating network-based IPS products, include those using techniques other than signature-based detection (such as virtual machine or sandbox-based approaches) for consideration.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No intranet DNS servers. Clients are configured for public DNS servers.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Domain Name System Hierarchy","question":"Deploy domain name systems (DNS) in a hierarchical, structured fashion, with all internal network client machines configured to send requests to intranet DNS servers, not to DNS servers located on the Internet. These internal DNS servers should be configured to forward requests they cannot resolve to DNS servers located on a protected DMZ. These DMZ servers, in turn, should be the only DNS servers allowed to send requests to the Internet.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"No proxy servers implemented.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"DMZ Proxy","question":"Design and implement network perimeters so that all outgoing web, file transfer protocol (FTP), and secure shell traffic to the Internet must pass through at least one proxy on a DMZ network. The proxy should support logging individual TCP sessions; blocking specific URLs, domain names, and IP addresses to implement a black list; and applying whitelists of allowed sites that can be accessed through the proxy while blocking all other sites. Organizations should force outbound traffic to the Internet through an authenticated proxy server on the enterprise perimeter. Proxies can also be used to encrypt all traffic leaving an organization.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"Segregation between network segments exists but no access controls implemented between segments.","domain":"Computer and Network Defense","objective":"Network Segmentation","question":"Whether the enterprise network has been segmented into multiple, separate trust zones to provide more granular control of system access and additional intranet boundary defenses.","section":"Boundary Security","source":"SANS 20 CSC","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - Via email.   Password breaches, Phishing attempts, viruses, etc...","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Reporting information security events","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are information security events reported through appropriate management channels as quickly as possible?","section":"Reporting information security events and weaknesses","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":66.66666666666666},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"customer_response":"Cam - Nothing formal.","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Reporting information security events","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Whether formal information security event reporting ‎procedure, Incident response and escalation procedure ‎is developed and implemented. ‎","section":"Reporting information security events and weaknesses","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Employee Handbook and IT Procedure manual instruct users to notify IT in the event of a virus alert.  Other suspected security events are not documented.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Reporting security weaknesses","policy_defined":{"id":2,"text":"Partial Written Policy","value":0.5},"question":"Whether there exists a procedure that ensures all ‎employees of information systems and services are ‎required to note and report any observed or suspected ‎security weakness in the system or services. ‎","section":"Reporting information security events and weaknesses","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":37.5},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"management responsibilities and procedures were not described in any provided documentation reviewed by the auditor.","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Responsibilities and procedures","question":"Whether management responsibilities and procedures ‎were established to ensure quick, effective and orderly ‎response to information security incidents. ‎","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"There is no proactive monitoring of alerts and vulnerabilities.  KACE is mostly implemented for monitoring of systems.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Automated","value":0.25},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Responsibilities and procedures","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Whether monitoring of systems, alerts and ‎vulnerabilities are used to detect information security ‎incidents. ‎","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":25},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"There is no incident response plan.","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Responsibilities and procedures","question":"Whether the objective of information security incident ‎management is agreed with the management.‎","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Cam - No.","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Learning from information security incidents","question":"Whether there is a mechanism in place to identify and ‎quantify the type, volume and costs of information ‎security incidents.","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"customer_response":"Cam - Have used this information to patch systems or correct system/application settings to prevent future issues.","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Learning from information security incidents","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Whether the information gained from the evaluation of ‎the past information security incidents are used to ‎identify recurring or high impact incidents. ‎","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":31.25},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - Depending on the severity of the incident - Yes.","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Collection of evidence","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether follow-up action against a person or ‎organization after an information security incident ‎involves legal action (either civil or criminal). ‎","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":0,"text":"Not Reported","value":0},"customer_response":"Cam - Instutional Knowledge","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Collection of evidence","policy_defined":{"id":0,"text":"No Policy","value":0},"question":"Whether evidence relating to the incident are collected, ‎retained and presented to conform to the rules for ‎evidence laid down in the relevant jurisdiction(s). ‎","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":6.25},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't follow-up with HR on this question.","customer_response":"Cam - HR may have forms","domain":"Information Security Incident Management","objective":"Collection of evidence","question":"Whether internal procedures are developed and followed when collecting and presenting evidence for the purpose of disciplinary action within the organization","section":"Management of information security incidents and improvements","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - IT requirements are addressed, but no specific IS requirements.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Including information security in the business continuity management process","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether there is a managed process in place that ‎addresses the information security requirements for ‎developing and maintaining business continuity ‎throughout the organization. ‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - IT requirements are addressed, but no specific IS requirements.&#10;&#10;Most IT assets are 3rd party, so no business critical assets are located at CLT.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Including information security in the business continuity management process","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether this process understands the risks the ‎organization is facing, identify business critical assets, ‎identify incident impacts, consider the implementation ‎of additional preventative controls and documenting ‎the business continuity plans addressing the security ‎requirements.‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - IT requirements are addressed, but no specific IS requirements.&#10;&#10;Most IT assets are 3rd party, so no business critical assets are located at CLT.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Business continuity and risk assessment","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether events that cause interruption to business ‎process is identified along with the probability and ‎impact of such interruptions and their consequence for ‎information security.‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Developing and implementing continuity plans including information security","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether plans were developed to maintain and restore ‎business operations, ensure availability of information ‎within the required level in the required time frame ‎following an interruption or failure to business ‎processes.","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - Business Continuity Authority Team.  8 people listed.\r\n\r\n- 6 different tests are to be performed annually.   New Plan just went into effect 06/01 and the new plan hasn't been tested yet.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Developing and implementing continuity plans including information security","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether the plan considers identification and ‎agreement of responsibilities, identification of ‎acceptable loss, implementation of recovery and ‎restoration procedure, documentation of procedure and ‎regular testing.‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Unclear of what this question is asking.  Need to revise or remove.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Business continuity planning framework","question":"Whether there is a single framework of Business ‎continuity plan.‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Unclear of what this question is asking.  Need to revise or remove.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Business continuity planning framework","question":"Whether this framework is maintained to ensure that ‎all plans are consistent and identify priorities for ‎testing and maintenance. ‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"auditor_notes":"Didn't have opportunity to reveiew the BCP during the audit.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Business continuity planning framework","question":"Whether business continuity plan addresses the ‎identified information security requirement. ‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - The Plan states that testing is to occur annually.  Not tested since new plan was implemented on 06/01.","domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Testing maintaining and re-assessing business continuity plans","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether Business continuity plans are tested regularly ‎to ensure that they are up to date and effective.‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"auditor_notes":"New BCP hasn't been tested according to the CIO.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Business Continuity Management","objective":"Testing maintaining and re-assessing business continuity plans","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Whether business continuity plan tests ensure that all ‎members of the recovery team and other relevant staff ‎are aware of the plans and their responsibility for ‎business continuity and information security and know ‎their role when plan is evoked. ‎","section":"Information security aspects of business continuity management","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":0},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":4,"text":"Automated on All Systems","value":1},"control_implemented":{"id":3,"text":"Implemented on Most Systems","value":0.75},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Partner with AllRegs (Part of Ellie Mae) to manage compliance policies.   Updates are pushed.  They provide templates for what certain requirements should look like and then MM customizes these.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are all relevant statutory, regulatory, and contractual requirements and the organization‟s approach to meet these requirements explicitly defined, documented, and kept up to date for each information system and the organization? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Identification of applicable legislation ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":100},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are the specific controls and individual responsibilities to meet these requirements similarly defined and documented? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Identification of applicable legislation ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Not sure MM has any Intellectual Property.\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers - No proprietary software or other products (Patents, etc...)","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are appropriate procedures implemented to ensure compliance with legislative, regulatory, and contractual requirements on the use of material in respect of which there may be intellectual property rights and on the use of proprietary software products? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Intellectual property rights (IPR)","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Not sure MM has any Intellectual Property.\r\n\r\nBrett Rodgers - Not Applicable","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are the following guidelines considered to protect any material that may be considered intellectual property:&#10;a) publishing an intellectual property rights compliance policy which defines the legal use of software and information products;&#10;b) acquiring software only through known and reputable sources, to ensure that copyright is not violated;&#10;c) maintaining awareness of policies to protect intellectual property rights, and giving notice of the intent to take disciplinary action against personnel breaching them;&#10;d) maintaining appropriate asset registers, and identifying all assets with requirements to protect intellectual property rights;&#10;e) maintaining proof and evidence of ownership of licenses, master disks, manuals, etc;&#10;f) implementing controls to ensure that any maximum number of users permitted is not exceeded;&#10;g) carrying out checks that only authorized software and licensed products are installed;&#10;h) providing a policy for maintaining appropriate license conditions;&#10;i) providing a policy for disposing or transferring software to others;&#10;j) using appropriate audit tools;&#10;k) complying with terms and conditions for software and information obtained from public networks;&#10;l) not duplicating, converting to another format or extracting from commercial recordings (film, audio) other than permitted by copyright law;&#10;m) not copying in full or in part, books, articles, reports or other documents, other than permitted by copyright law?","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Intellectual property rights (IPR)","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - safeguards such as fire-proof safes and offsite storage (Iron Mountain) are used to protect data.   Consumer Privacy Policy adddresses data protection.  Last updated 08/2015.&#10;&#10;PC Lender stores data offsite and on redundant storage.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are important records protected from loss, destruction, and falsification, in accordance with statutory, regulatory, contractual, and business requirements? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"auditor_notes":"Consider adding further detail for data/record types.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Consumer Privacy Policy adddresses record types.  Could be further refined.  Last updated 08/2015.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are records categorized into record types, e.g. accounting records, database records, transaction logs, audit logs, and operational procedures, each with details of retention periods and type of storage media, e.g. paper, microfiche, magnetic, optical? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"cryptographic keying material not utilized.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are any related cryptographic keying material and programs associated with encrypted archives or digital signatures, also stored to enable decryption of the records for the length of time the records are retained? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Is consideration given to the possibility of deterioration of media used for storage of records? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are storage and handling procedures implemented in accordance with manufacturer’s recommendations? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Where electronic storage media are chosen, are procedures to ensure the ability to access data (both media and format readability) throughout the retention period included, to safeguard against loss due to future technology change? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Are data storage systems chosen such that required data can be retrieved in an acceptable timeframe and format, depending on the requirements to be fulfilled? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Does the system of storage and handling ensure clear identification of records and of their retention period as defined by national or regional legislation or regulations, if applicable? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Does this system permit appropriate destruction of records after that period if they are not needed by the organization? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"PC Lender meets all regulatory requirements.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Is data protection and privacy ensured as required in relevant legislation, regulations, and, if applicable, contractual clauses? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Protection of organizational records ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - safeguards are referenced in Document and Email Retention Doc and Cosumer Privacy Doc.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Has an organizational data protection and privacy policy been developed and implemented? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Data protection and privacy of personal information ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Stored on Policy/Procedure page on the Corporate Intranet site.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Has this policy been communicated to all persons involved in the processing of personal information? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Data protection and privacy of personal information ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":5,"text":"Partial"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Unsure;  Verify with IT.\r\n\r\nCam - Myself, Will Simons, and Mike McCrae are the POCs, but no formal policy is communicated to users.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Has a person responsible, such as a data protection officer, who will provide guidance to managers, users, and service providers on their individual responsibilities and the specific procedures to be followed, been appointed? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Data protection and privacy of personal information ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":25},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Monthly compliance training covers all topics related to relevant laws and regulations.   Customer Data Protection awareness training isn't on the schedule for the rest of the year, but it may have happened earlier this year.    Managers may require associates to take webinars or courses online that are above required training.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Is responsibility for handling personal information and ensuring awareness of the data protection principles dealt with in accordance with relevant legislation and regulations? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Data protection and privacy of personal information ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"customer_response":"CAM - PC Lender meets all regulatory requirements for protecting NPI.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect personal information implemented? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Data protection and privacy of personal information ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Acceptable Use Policy covered in Employee Handbook.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - Yes.  Employee Handbook covers this.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"Are users deterred from using information processing facilities for unauthorized purposes? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"customer_response":"Cam - IT Approves of all Information Processing methods.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Does management approve the use of information processing facilities? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":0,"text":"Not Automated","value":0},"control_implemented":{"id":1,"text":"Parts of Policy Implemented","value":0.25},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"Is any use of these facilities for non-business purposes without management approval, or for any unauthorized purposes, regarded as improper use of the facilities? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":4,"text":"Implemented on All Systems","value":1},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Cam - Covered in Employee Handbook.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":4,"text":"Approved Written Policy","value":1},"question":"If any unauthorized activity is identified by monitoring or other means, is this activity brought to the attention of the individual manager concerned for consideration of appropriate disciplinary and/or legal action? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Is legal advice sought and taken before implementing monitoring procedures? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Cam - No.  Monitoring is not currently in place.  Most people probably don't know their level of access.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are all users aware of the precise scope of their permitted access and of the monitoring in place to detect unauthorized use? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Is this achieved by giving users written authorization, a copy of which assigned by the user and securely retained by the organization? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Team Leads email passwords and computer passwords for their team members.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are employees of an organization, contractors, and third party users advised that no access will be permitted except that which is authorized? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Prevention of misuse of information processing facilities ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are cryptographic controls used in compliance with all relevant agreements, laws, and regulations? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Regulation of cryptographic controls ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Are the following items considered for compliance with the relevant agreements, laws, and regulations:&#10;a) restrictions on import and/or export of computer hardware and software for performing cryptographic functions;&#10;b) restrictions on import and/or export of computer hardware and software which is designed to have cryptographic functions added to it;&#10;c) restrictions on the usage of encryption;&#10;d) mandatory or discretionary methods of access by the&#10;countries' authorities to information encrypted by hardware or software to provide confidentiality of content?","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Regulation of cryptographic controls ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Legal is consulted by the Compliance Department for all matters related to this topic.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","policy_defined":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"question":"Is legal advice sought to ensure compliance with national laws and regulations? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Regulation of cryptographic controls ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with legal requirements ","question":"Before encrypted information or cryptographic controls are moved to another country, is legal advice also taken? ","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Regulation of cryptographic controls ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.1","status":-1},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Unsure - check with CIO or someone from HR to qualify the answer.\r\n\r\nCam - Probably not.  Seen in the Employee Handbook and probably not reviewed again.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Do managers ensure that all security procedures within their area of responsibility are carried out correctly to achieve compliance with security policies and standards? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Compliance with security policies and standards ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Yes, but check with CIO or someone from HR to qualify the answer. \r\n\r\nCam - Probably not.  Seen in the Employee HAndbook and probably not reviewed again.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Do managers review the compliance of information processing within their area of responsibility with the appropriate security policies, standards, and any other security requirements? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Compliance with security policies and standards ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Policy is in place (Employee handbook), but cannot verify managers perform these actions.\r\n\r\nCam - No.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"If any non-compliance is found as a result of the review, do managers: &#10;a) determine the causes of the non-compliance; &#10;b) evaluate the need for actions to ensure that non-compliance do not recur; &#10;c) determine and implement appropriate corrective action; &#10;d) review the corrective action taken. ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Compliance with security policies and standards ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Policy is in place (Employee handbook), but cannot verify managers perform these actions.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Are results of reviews and corrective actions carried out by managers recorded and are these records maintained? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Compliance with security policies and standards ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"customer_response":"Lee Rhodes - Policy is in place (Employee handbook), but cannot verify managers perform these actions.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Do managers report the results to the persons carrying out the independent reviews, when the independent review takes place in the area of their responsibility? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Compliance with security policies and standards ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Are information systems regularly checked for compliance with security implementation standards?","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Technical compliance checking ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":0},{"answer":{"id":1,"text":"No"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Is technical compliance checking performed either manually (supported by appropriate software tools, if necessary) by an experienced system engineer, and/or with the assistance of automated tools, which generate a technical report for subsequent interpretation by a technical specialist? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Technical compliance checking ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":0},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"If penetration tests or vulnerability assessments are used is caution exercised as such activities could lead to a compromise of the security of the system? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Technical compliance checking ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Are such tests planned, documented and repeatable? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Technical compliance checking ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Compliance with security policies and standards, and technical compliance ","question":"Are any technical compliance check only carried out by competent, authorized persons, or under the supervision of such persons? ","reason":"The security of information systems should be regularly reviewed. &#10;Such reviews should be performed against the appropriate security policies and the technical platforms and information systems should be audited for compliance with applicable security implementation standards and documented security controls. &#10;","section":"Technical compliance checking ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.2","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Information systems audit considerations ","question":"Are audit requirements and activities involving checks on operational systems carefully planned and agreed to minimize the risk of disruptions to business processes? ","reason":"There should be controls to safeguard operational systems and audit tools during information systems audits. &#10;Protection is also required to safeguard the integrity and prevent misuse of audit tools. &#10;","section":"Information system audit controls ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.3","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Information systems audit considerations ","question":"Are the following guidelines observed:&#10;a) audit requirements should be agreed with appropriate management;&#10;b) the scope of the checks should be agreed and controlled;&#10;c) the checks should be limited to read-only access to software and data;&#10;d) access other than read-only should only be allowed for isolated copies of system files, which should be erased when the audit is completed, or given appropriate protection if there is an obligation to keep such files under audit documentation requirements;&#10;e) resources for performing the checks should be explicitly identified and made available;&#10;f) requirements for special or additional processing should be identified and agreed;&#10;g) all access should be monitored and logged to produce a reference trail; the use of time stamped reference trails should be considered for critical data or systems;&#10;h) all procedures, requirements, and responsibilities should be documented;&#10;i) the person(s) carrying out the audit should be independent of the activities audited?","reason":"There should be controls to safeguard operational systems and audit tools during information systems audits. &#10;Protection is also required to safeguard the integrity and prevent misuse of audit tools. &#10;","section":"Information system audit controls ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.3","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Information systems audit considerations ","question":"Is access to information systems audit tools protected to prevent any possible misuse or compromise? ","reason":"There should be controls to safeguard operational systems and audit tools during information systems audits. &#10;Protection is also required to safeguard the integrity and prevent misuse of audit tools. &#10;","section":"Protection of information systems audit tools ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.3","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":3,"text":"Not Reviewed"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Information systems audit considerations ","question":"Are information systems audit tools, e.g. software or data files, separated from development and operational systems and not held in tape libraries or user areas, unless given an appropriate level of additional protection? ","reason":"There should be controls to safeguard operational systems and audit tools during information systems audits. &#10;Protection is also required to safeguard the integrity and prevent misuse of audit tools. &#10;","section":"Protection of information systems audit tools ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.3","status":-2},{"answer":{"id":0,"text":"Yes"},"auditor_notes":"Observed during our audit &#10;- temporary admin accounts were provided&#10;- admin passwords were changed and then reset&#10;- admin passwords were entered into scan tools w/o providing them to us.","control_automated_or_technically_enforced":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_implemented":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"control_reported_to_business":{"id":5,"text":"Not Applicable"},"domain":"Compliance","objective":"Information systems audit considerations ","policy_defined":{"id":1,"text":"Informal Policy","value":0.25},"question":"If third parties are involved in an audit, there might be a risk of misuse of audit tools by these third parties, and information being accessed by this third party organization. Are controls considered to address this risk, and any consequences, such as immediately changing passwords disclosed to the auditors, taken? ","reason":"There should be controls to safeguard operational systems and audit tools during information systems audits. &#10;Protection is also required to safeguard the integrity and prevent misuse of audit tools. &#10;","section":"Protection of information systems audit tools ","source":"ISO/IEC 27002:2013 Information technology, 15.3","status":100},{"answer":{"id":2,"text":"Not Applicable"},"customer_response":"Not done with nonaffiliated third parties;  Only affiliates.   No annual disclosure to customer since once the loan process is completed, the customer data is not disclosed.","domain":"Compliance","objective":"Privacy Protection","question":"If the organization discloses nonpublic personal information of its customers to affiliates to nonaffiliated third parties - do they provide a clear disclosure to the customer, at least annually, of the organization's policies and practices for disclosing nonpublic personal information.","reason":"The design, operation, use, and management of information systems may be subject to statutory, &#10;regulatory and contractual security requirements. &#10;Advice on specific legal requirements should be sought from the organization‟s legal advisers, or suitably qualified legal practitioners. Legislative requirements vary from country to country and may vary for information created in one country that is transmitted to another country (i.e. trans-border data flow). ","section":"Disclosure of customer information","source":"(§ 6803(a), Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA))","status":-1}]
